<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Merging one or more tracks">
	<intro
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/GroomingTrackData.html#CombineTrackSections">
		<description>In the previous tutorial, we generated two track
			sections and, though they are separate tracks on our plot, we know that they belong to
			the same vessel; we will now combine them into a single track.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Using the <b>Outline</b> view, use press the <b>Ctrl</b> key and click to select both tracks.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Right-click on one of the
			selected tracks and select <b>Group tracks into TMA_xyz</b> (it doesn&apos;t matter which one you
			select).
			<br/><b>3.</b> The tracks will merge into one (the other track will disappear). However,
			there is still that large &apos;turn gap&apos; remaining. We will use Debrief to infill, or
			bridge, that gap.</description>
	</intro>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/GroomingTrackData.html#CombineTrackSections"
		title="Provide infill positions">
		<description>Debrief is able to link the two track sections
			by filling the gap between them.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click to expand <b>Track:TMA_xyz</b> and you will see it
			contains T<b>rack Segments</b> (<b>2 items</b>).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Expand this, and you will see two tracks with
			different numbers of items (in mine, I have <b>220415.22</b> (<b>17 items</b>) and <b>220503.26</b> (<b>20
			items</b>)).
			<br/><b>3.</b> Select both tracks (<b>Ctrl+click</b>)
			<br/><b>4.</b> Right-click on either one and select
			<b>Generate infill segment</b>.
			<br/><b>5.</b> You&apos;ll see a new segment appear both in the <b>Outline</b> view and
			in the plot.
			<br/>Notice that the infill segment is shown as a dotted line. This indicates
			that this track segment is not based on any real bearing data, it has just been calculated
			to join both tracks.
			<br/>Also, if you look in the <b>Outline</b> view at the <b>Track Segments</b>, you
			will see the three individual tracks listed. Take note of the icons: two are straight-line
			tracks, and the other shows multiple turns.</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/GroomingTrackData.html#JoinTrackSections"
		title="Merge tracks">
		<description>You can continue to keep your
			target track represented as three or more track segments for as long as you like. But, when
			you need to export the data for presentation or subsequent analysis then you must merge
			them:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Select the parent item for the track segments (<b>Track segments (3 items</b>)
			<br/><b>2.</b> Right-click on it and select <b>Merge all track segments</b> to merge the tracks.
		</description>
		<subitem
			label="Note: If the track sections cover overlapping time periods the merge operation will fail. Just decide which track is the more accurate track and trim the time period of the other track, then start the merge operation again. If track overlap is a frequently occuring problem, please contact the maintainer and a merge algorithm will be developed."
			skip="true">
		</subitem>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
