<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Generate a target track">
	<intro>
		<description>This cheat sheet guides you through creating a target track segment from bearing data to represent a period of straight-line
			motion; and can be interpreted as a <b>Manual Target Motion Analysis (TMA) Solution</b>.
			<br/>We will be using the track and sensor
			data from the previous example, so if you closed it, reopen it now.
			<br/>In this tutorial,
			we will be concentrating on the plot, so you can close the <b>Grid Editor</b> window.</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Deciding the contact period">
		<description>A capable analyst will be able to recognise a couple of periods of steady
			bearing rate that lend themselves to being the basis of TMA solutions.
			<br/>The first period of cuts we&apos;re going to use here are the first 15 or so sensor cuts. We can see that
			at the end of this period, there are 2 bearing lines very close together and then a gap,
			a small group of 3 bearing lines, and then another gap. After this second gap, there is
			a period of about 10 unsteady cuts, and then another steady period; we&apos;ll be using
			that for a solution a little later also.</description>
	</item>

	<item title="Highlight contacts">
		<description>Let's change the color of
			the contacts to make our first solution easier to see and work on:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Identify the last bearing line you will use for the first period of steady bearing data.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Double-click somewhere on that bearing line and it will be highlighted in the <b>Outline</b> view (I
			selected the data point named <b>090722 044319</b>).
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click on that item in the <b>Outline</b> view
			to select it.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Now, scroll back up to the start of the sensor data, hold down the <b>Shift</b>
			key, and then click on the first entry - this period of sensor data is now selected.
			<br/><b>5.</b> To change the colour, right-click anywhere on the selected group and select <b>Multiple
			items</b> > <b>Color</b> > <b>Orange</b>.
			<br/>The bearing lines in the plot area, and the selected items in
			the <b>Outline</b> view will turn orange.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Generate the TMA segment">
		<description>Now we&apos;re going to create
			a solution from this selected (orange) data. When we generate a TMA segment based on
			sensor data, Debrief creates a track segment of steady course/speed data points, with
			one data-point at the time of each sensor cut used to generate the segment. Debrief has
			a <b>Generate TMA Wizard</b> to help you with this.
			<br/>With the set of data still selected in the
			<b>Outline</b> view (or reselect it if you&apos;ve lost the selection):
			<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click on the
			selected sensor data and select <b>Generate TMA solution from selected cuts</b>. The <b>Generate
			TMA Segment</b> dialog will show, asking you to <b>specify the offset to the track start</b>.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Enter a range of <b>1 nautical mile (nm)</b> and you can leave the bearing of <b>300.8</b>
			(it&apos;s using the bearing from our first sensor cut).
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click <b>Next</b> and you will see the
			<b>initial solution</b> dialog.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Based on our understanding and analysis of the sensor fan in
			the plot area, enter <b>220</b> for the initial estimate of the course and <b>6 knots</b> for the
			speed estimate.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Click on <b>Finish</b>.
			A red track will appear on the plot, labelled with
			the TMA solution and the time of the first cut used (<b>TMA_220415.22</b> on my plot — all
			solutions have times in their name to make it easier to manage).</description>
	</item>
	<item skip="true" title="Recognise track data">
		<description>We will now look at the track data for this TMA solution in the <b>Outline</b> view.
			<br/>First, expand the new track (mine is called <b>Track:TMA_220415.22</b>) in the <b>Outline</b> view and you will see
			the <b>Positions (17 items)</b> child item.
			<br/>If you look at the icon for this particular item,
			you will see that it shows a straight-line section of data with a tiny red compass rose
			on it. However, if you also look at the equivalent object for <b> <b>Track:NONSUCH</b> </b>, you can see
			that it shows a non-straight-line set of positions (with 2 turns).
			<br/>Also, note that on
			the plot, the name of the <b>Track:NONSUCH</b> TMA segment is shown in italics, to denote that
			it&apos;s not based on actual position recordings.</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/analysing_data.html#assigning_tracks"
		title="Put the tracks on the tote">
		<description>To view residuals, we must tell Debrief which is the ownship and which is the target.
			Debrief can hold many more than two tracks, but we must tell it which two tracks we
			want to compare.
			<br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, select  <b>Track:NONSUCH</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view toolbar, click on the <b>1 (primary)</b> button.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Now, click on the <b>Track_xxxx</b> item (mine is <b>Track:TMA_220415.22</b>)
			<br/><b>4.</b> Click on the <b>2 (secondary)</b> button on the
			toolbar.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Now, switch to the <b>Track Tote</b> view (<b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Track Tote</b> if it is
			not open) and you&apos;ll see it contains both our primary and our secondary tracks.
			<br/>Debrief now knows which tracks we wish to compare.</description>
		<command required="false"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.mwc.cmap.tote.views.ToteView)" />
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/formatting_data.html#track_shifting"
		title="Manipulate the track segment">
		<description>We will now manipulate the track segment to minimise bearing and frequency residuals.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Drag Track Segment</b> button on the Debrief toolbar or press <b>ALt+1</b> to display the <b>Bearing
			Residuals</b> view.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> you can resize or move views by moving your mouse
			over the sides of a view and, when the cursor changes to a multi-directional arrow, you can drag in either of the directions indicated; or you can click on the view tab and drag the view to another part of the display, or even to another connected monitor.
.
			<br/><b>2.</b> In the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> view are the four drag operation buttons that
			control how you drag the track. The labelled functions are:
			<br/>     ◦ <b>Translate</b> - you can drag either end of the track: this changes range and bearing from
			the source, but maintains target course and speed.
			<br/>     ◦<b>Rotate</b> - you can drag either
			end or from the middle of the track: doing so maintains the target speed but changes the
			target course.
			<br/>     ◦<b>Stretch</b> - you can also drag either end or the middle of the track:
			stretch allows you to maintain the target course but change the target speed. If the
			centre-point of the track is dragged, the track moves in and out, adjusting as necessary
			to adhere to the start/end points on the host platform bearing fan.
			<br/>     ◦<b>Shear</b> - you can drag either end or the middle of the track: this option allows you to change both target
			course and speed.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> only the <b>Translate</b> and <b>Rotate</b> operations are available for all
			track sections. Only the <b>Stretch</b> and <b>Shear</b> operations are suitable for application to
			<b>straight-line TMA Segments</b>. To help you, the hand cursor will only turn green over
			straight-line TMA Segment hot-spots.
			<br/>Even though you select the above drag options in
			the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> view, these selections are used in conjunction with the drag
			buttons from the main toolbar:<b> Drag Track Segment</b>, <b>Drag Component</b>, and <b>Drag Whole
			Feature</b>, and all drag functions are carried out on tracks within the plot area. This
			gives you a huge array of options and capabilities.
			<br/>By default, the cursor hand is
			brown. When it is this colour, you cannot modify the track from this particular point because it
			isn&apos;t a hot-spot. If you move the cursor over a point on the track which is a hot-spot
			and does allow you to manipulate (or move) that point, the cursor will become
			green. As mentioned above, this will either be at the end, and/or
			in the middle of a track.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Now, select <b>Shear mode</b> and <b>Drag Track Segment</b> (<b>Alt+1</b>) and
			practice dragging the ends of the track to optimise the bearing errors in the <b>Bearing
			Residuals</b> windowview.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> remember, here you are trying to reduce the distance between the
			calculated bearing and the measured bearing.</description>
		<subitem
			label="Review bearing residuals.  When you enter drag-track mode, the view Bearing Residuals view is opened for you - so you can track the current residual errors."
			skip="true">
		</subitem>
		<subitem
			label="Review frequency residuals.  If you do are using data that contains frequency measurements, open the Frequency Residuals view to track the difference between measured and predicted frequency (taking ownship and target doppler into account)."
			skip="true">
			<command required="false"
				serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.mwc.debrief.track_shift.views.FrequencyResidualsView)" />
		</subitem>
	</item>
	<item title="Generate second TMA segment">
		<description>Looking at the
			sensor data, it would appear that the turn is represented by about 13 cuts before a
			further straight line section of data.
			<br/>As you look at the fan of sensor data, you can
			see there&apos;s an early block of bearing lines that are roughly parallel. Then, towards the
			end of the track, the bearing lines appear to converge steadily around a single point.
			In between these two periods of steady data, the lines jump around a little, and this
			represents the period where the target vessel is changing course and/or speed.
			<br/>Now, let&apos;s work with the plot again…
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the first sensor cut of the second steady set
			of bearings - that cut will be highlighted in the <b>Outline</b> view (I selected <b>090722
			050326</b>).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Now scroll down to the end of the data and <b>Shift-click</b> the last sensor cut.
			We&apos;ve now selected the cuts to be used for the second track segment.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Right-click on
			one of the selected items and select <b>Multiple items</b> > <b>Color</b> > <b>Green</b>. The cuts will turn
			green.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Right-click again on the selected cuts and select <b>Generate TMA solution from
			selected cuts</b>, and complete the wizard once again:
			<br/>     <b>i.</b> Enter a range of <b>1 nautical mile</b>
			(<b>nm</b>) and you can leave the bearing of <b>292.3</b> as is (it&apos;s using the bearing from our first
			sensor cut in this selection).
			<br/>     <b>ii.</b> Click <b>Next</b> and you will see the <b>initial solution</b>
			dialog.
			<br/>     <b>iii.</b> Based on our understanding and analysis of the sensor fan in the plot area,
			enter <b>220</b> for the initial estimate of the course (but it won&apos;t be, because the earlier
			spacing in the bearing fan shows us that the vessel has turned) and <b>6 knots</b> for the
			speed estimate.
			<br/>     <b>iv.</b> Click on <b>Finish</b> and the second track will be plotted.
			<br/>As already mentioned,
			the new track is probably wrong due to the earlier turn, but we can manipulate the
			track and see what solution we can arrive at. </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Refine second solution">
		<description> Now, locate this new solution in the <b>Outline</b> view:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the track to
			select it (mine is called <b>Track:TMA_220503.26</b>)
			<br/><b>2.</b> Then click on the <b>2</b> (<b>secondary</b>) button
			on the toolbar to designate it as the secondary track. As soon as you mark it as
			secondary, you will see it listed in the <b>Track Tote</b> view.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Now, start manipulating
			and refining this solution.</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
