<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Groom sensor data">
	<intro>
		<description>
			This cheat sheet guides you through creating and preparing the ownship sensor data for producing <b>Target Motion Analysis (TMA)</b> tracks.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Load datafiles">
		<description> For this tutorial we will be using a new set of datafiles.
			<br/>In the <b>Navigator</b>:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Go to the <b>sample_data</b> > <b>S2R</b> folder.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Double-click on the <b>nonsuch.rep</b> file to display the <b>Track Mode</b> dialog.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Select <b>Dead Reckoning (DR)...</b> from the dialog and click on
			<b>OK</b>. The ownship track will load into the plot (<b>Track:NONSUCH</b> in the <b>Outline View</b>).
			<br/><b>4.</b> Click on the <b>Fit to Window</b> button.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Now drag in the <b>sensor.dsf</b> file from the <b>Navigator</b> view.
			<br/><b>6.</b> The <b>Import Sensor Data</b> dialog will display.
			<br/><b>7.</b> You can go through the tabs by clicking on the <b>Next</b> button this time round you can just click <b>Finish</b> to accept
			the default options.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> as the plot area can quickly become cluttered, the data from the <b>sensor.dsf</b> file is not shown on the plot by default.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Make sensor data visible">
		<description>While this is the default option, we now wish to see the sensor data we&apos;ve
			just imported.
			<br/>So, in the <b>Outline</b> view:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the down-arrow next to <b>Track:NONSUCH</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click on <b>Sensors (1 items)</b> to expand it.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click on <b>Sensor:Sensor_A (52 items)</b> to select it.
			<br/><b>4.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view toolbar, click on the tick button (<b>Reveal selected
			items</b>), and all the sensor data will appear (we call these bearing fans).
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Resolve ambiguity">
		<description> In our data, you can see there are 2 bearing fans: 1 radiating out WNW, and the
			other NNE. Intelligence and experience tells us that our actual contact is off to the
			NW.
			Now we need to understand what is actually happening here. If we open
			the <b>Time Controller</b> view and drag the time slider back and forth, we&apos;ll see our current
			position highlight moving from top-right (the start point), to bottom left (the end
			point). As such, the NW block of sensor data is to the right, or starboard, of the Nonsuch track.
			<i>NoPrint</i>(Use <b>Click to perform</b> below if you wish, to open the Time Controller)<i>NoPrint</i>.
		</description>
		<command required="false"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.mwc.cmap.TimeController.views.TimeController)" />
	</item>
	<item title="Remove ambiguous data">
		<description>
			Now that we know which sensor data we do need, we can remove that which we don&apos;t:
			<br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, expand the <b>SENSOR_A</b> dataset
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select all of the child items by clicking on the top value, scroll to the bottom of the list and then press and
			hold the <b>Shift</b> key on your keyboard while clicking on the bottom value - this will
			select all 52 sensor items.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Right-click on any of the entries and select <b>Keep
			starboard bearing</b>; the port bearings will disappear from view.
			<br/>Next, we need to edit the raw sensor data.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open grid editor">
		<description> One way of editing the raw sensor data is by using the <b>Grid Editor</b>.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show view</b> > <b>Grid Editor</b>.
			<br/><b>2.</b> The <b>Grid Editor</b> view will appear, but it will be
			blank until we indicate the data to edit.</description>
		<command required="false"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=com.pml.grid.editor)" />
	</item>
	<item title="Indicate data to edit">
		<description> The grid editor reflects the current selection in the <b>Outline</b> view.
			However, if the selected items in the <b>Outline</b> view are not suitable for editing in the
			grid format, nothing will be seen; as we have just seen in this tutorial, after hiding the port
			bearings and opening the grid editor, the grid is actually empty.
			<br/>To populate the grid area: click on the Track Segment <b>220350.04 (826 items)</b>, just under the
			<b>Track:NONSUCH</b> in the <b>Outline</b> view. The grid edit view will now populate.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> this behaviour can be cancelled by clicking on the lock icon in the grid editor toolbar. If
			you open the <b>Track:NONSUCH</b> item and select the positions, you&apos;ll see them appear in the
			grid editor.
			<br/>Now click on the sensor data for <b>Track:NONSUCH</b> > <b>Sensor:SENSOR_A(52
			items)</b> — the data from this track will now populate the grid editor.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title=" Tidy your interface">
		<description>As mentioned previously, the interface can become easily cluttered. However, if
			you have a dual monitor and want all the windows and views open, you can
			drag-and-drop views onto your other screen by clicking and holding the individual view tabs,
			and then moving them or resizing them as required.</description>
	</item>
	<item skip="false" title="View the data">
		<description>he scrollbar on the right-hand side lets you move forwards and
			backwards through the data (the newest items are shown at the top). Most cells in the
			grid are editable, including the date; blue and red buttons are available in the
			toolbar to add or remove rows.
			<br/>Clicking on the blue <b>Add</b> button will insert a duplicate
			of the currently selected row immediately beneath it - a major time-saver compared with
			manually entering data.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Work on an attribute">
		<description>In addition to straight-forward text-editing of data, selecting an attribute offers further editing capabilities. For
			example:
			<br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Frequency</b> column, click on the header cell itself (where it says
			&apos;Frequency&apos;): you&apos;ll see a graph appear in the bottom half of the view. This
			graph is a &apos;waterfall&apos; display of frequency, with the most recent value at the top.
			<br/><b>2.</b> <b>Zoom in</b> on data by dragging your mouse on the graph using a top-left to bottom-right
			motion.
			<br/><b>3.</b> <b>Zoom out</b> by dragging bottom-right to top-left.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Fix dodgy frequency observation">
		<description> Fix dodgy frequency observation
			If you zoom out to look at all the frequency data, you&apos;ll see that while this data seems
			fairly constant near the top of the dataset (along the 49.99 frequency value), there are
			occasions where the data value seems too low (when viewed in the context of a
			steady ownship track).
			<br/>We can fix an errant data point by dragging it
			into a better position.
			<br/><b>1.</b> <b>Zoom in</b> on the data around the time <b>05:20</b>. You will see that
			the data-point at <b>05:19:11</b> is signifocantly lower than its neighbours.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Move this data
			point by clicking inside the square data point and dragging the symbol to align with it&apos;s neighbours. Remember, you can zoom in multiple times for greater
			precision.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> if the neighbours were in a steady drift, you could align them by sight
			far more accurately.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Smooth period of data">
		<description>To smooth a block of data, we need to switch to bearing data:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Bearing</b> column, the graph of bearing data
			will appear.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Around the <b>05:10</b> to <b>05:20</b> period on the graph, you will see three
			step-ups in the data, zoom in on these three steps.
			<br/>It appears that the last smooth data
			point before the steps is at <b>05:10:44</b>, and the first after the steps is at <b>05:21:30</b>.
			We&apos;re going to interpolate the data points between these two values.
			<br/>To do so, we must tell Debrief which points we intend to keep:
			<br/><b>1.</b> In the grid, the top half of the
			editor, click on the empty space to the left of row <b>05:10:44</b>.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Now, hold down the <b>Ctrl</b>
			key and click on row <b>05:21:30</b>. As soon as you do this, the <b>Interpolate</b> (<b>calculator</b>)
			button in the grid editor toolbar will be enabled.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click on the <b>Interpolate</b> button and
			the bearings for the selected data points will be smoothed along that curve.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> you can select <b>Undo</b> from the edit menu or press <b>Ctrl+Z</b> on your keyboard to undo an
			interpolation operation.</description>
	</item>
	<item skip="true" title="Getting clever with interpolation">
		<description>In the previous step, we only selected a single point at each end of what could be considered poor data.
			However, there are two other, more advanced ways of doing an interpolation.
			<br/><b>1.</b> If we had selected multiple points at the ends of the dodgy data, Debrief would have fit the
			interpolated values to a cubic spline passing through the selected points.
			<br/><b>2.</b> If we had selected one or more points in the middle of the dodgy data (in addition to
			point(s) at the ends) then Debrief would have fitted a curve through the end and
			midpoints of the dataset.
			<br/>Now that we&apos;ve tidied the sensor data, we can move on.</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/sensor_data.html#SensorOffsetsEditor"
		title="Set array offset">
		<description>As you will see, the sensor data is ambiguous; this can happen when the
			data has been produced by a towed array.
			<br/>In this current scenario, Debrief is plotting
			the sensor cuts against the attack datum of the platform, but we need to apply an offset
			of 451 m in this particular example for this sensor (this is -451m). To do this:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Select <b>Sensor:SENSOR_A</b> in the <b>Outline</b> view
			<br/><b>2.</b> Open the <b>Properties</b> view and you will see the
			<b>SensorOffset</b> attribute. Enter -451 in this field, then press enter. As you do so, the
			bearings on the plot will adjust to reflect this change.
			<br/><b>3.</b> To see where the current array centre is, in the <b>Outline</b> view, click on <b>Track:NONSUCH</b>
			<br/><b>4.</b> In the <b>Properties</b> view under <b>Format</b>, you will see <b>PlotArrayCentre</b>, change it to <b>Yes</b>. A cross will appear
			astern of the current submarine location.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> we will use the track and sensor
			data from this tutorial in the next tutorial, so ensure you save it if you&apos;re going to
			take a break and move onto something else.</description>
		<command required="false"
			serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.eclipse.ui.views.PropertySheet)" />
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/GroomingTrackData.html#ResamplingData"
		skip="true" title="Reduce data density">
		<description>Though it isn&apos;t necessary for this particular scenario, Debrief does allow you to reduce the
			density of sensor data:
			<br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, right-click on <b>Sensor:SENSOR_A</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> In the drop-down menu, click on <b>SENSOR_A</b> > <b>Visible Frequency</b>, then select the filter required.
			<br/>Adjusting these options will filter out sensor data and hide sensor observations between
			the specified frequency. The sensor cuts are not deleted, they are just hidden; they can be made
			visible again by selecting a smaller, visible frequency.
			<b>Note: </b>another way of doing this
			is to right-click the parent track, <b>Track:NONSUCH</b>, select <b>Resample data at</b>, and
			select the required period.
			<br/>We&apos;ve now got a track with lovely smooth sensor data.</description>
	</item>
	<item
		title="Save your data">
		<description>As mentioned earlier, this sensor data and track will be required for the next
			tutorial; if you don&apos;t intend to jump straight onto it, be sure to save this file:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>File</b> > <b>Save</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> You have to save the file with the dpf extension, so select the
			folder where you will save the fil
			<br/><b>3.</b> Enter the filename and click <b>OK</b></description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
