<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Executing the scenario">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Right, we&apos;ve defined the inputs to the simulation.  Now to run them.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Open Scenario Controller.">
      <description>
         We manage scenarios from the Scenario Controller view.  If it isn&apos;t open, open the <b>Window/Show View</b> menu, then select <b>Scenario Controller</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Load the data files">
         <description> 
      Next, individually (or collectively) drag and drop our new scenario and control file onto the scenario controller. Once they&apos;ve loaded, you&apos;ll see their filenames in the <b>Scenario file</b> and <b>Control file</b> labels.  You will also see the scenario itself listed in the table in the lower half of the scenario controller tab.  Only one scenario is listed - that&apos;s because our control file didn&apos;t specify that scenario generation should happen.  Select this the <b>Name</b> field for this single scenario, and you will see the <b>Init</b> button has become enabled - ready to start the run.      </description>
   </item>
  <item
         title="Open the plot viewer">
      <description>
         Just to give a warm feeling that something&apos;s actually happening, open a graphical plot of the scenario by clicking on the Scenario Controller&apos;s globe icon. You&apos;ll see the fishing vessel shown in the centre of the screen, with it&apos;s status shown as inactive.  If the fishing vessel doesn&apos;t appear, just select the <b>Status</b> field in the table, then the <b>Name</b> field again - to indicate to the plot what we want to look at.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Open the Layer Manager">
      <description>
         You can also have a look at the scenario in a tree-type view by opening the Layer Manager.  You&apos;ll see that the simulation is represented as two top-level items, one for the scenario itself, and the other for the scenario controller (generator).
      </description>
   </item>
      <item
         title="Start the run">
      <description>
         Right, now we&apos;re ready to go.  Click on <b>Init</b> in the Scenario Controller panel - this will configure the scenario listeners.  (the <b>Step</b> and <b>Play</b> buttons should now become enabled).  Next, click once on the <b>Step</b> button.
<br/>
A number of things will now have happened.  The Scenario Controller will show the scenario time - and the icons on the plot will have moved.
      </description>
   </item>   <item
         title="Move forward">
      <description>
         Now, repeatedly click on the <b>Step</b> button and you&apos;ll see the scenario steadily move forward in time - on all relevant views. On the plot, you&apos;ll also see that the vessel are annotated with their current status.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Start scenario playing forward">
      <description>
         Now we can get the scenario to play forwards on its own - by clicking on the <b>Play</b> button.  You&apos;ll see the scenario start to move forward - incrementing by the 10 minute time step we specified earlier. Zoom out further if the fisherman has wandered off your viewpoint. <b>Note</b>, if you don&apos;t have a zoom out button on the toolbar, select <b>Open Perspective</b> from the View menu, and select <b>Tactical Analysis</b> from the perspectives offered.  ASSET will re-adjust itself to show the Debrief toolbar, after which you can then switch back to <b>Tactical Simulation</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Monitor a participant">
      <description>
         There&apos;s one last interactive thing to look at. Open the <b>Vessel Monitor</b> view - this shows us the current status of any participant.  We instruct the vessel monitor which vessel to display by selecting it in the Layer Manager.  Open the tree node representing the scenario (prob <b>Cheat sheet scenario</b>), then select <b>Fisher One</b> from it.  You&apos;ll see the Vessel monitor update to show this participant.
<br/>
If the scenario has finished before you get this far, just click on Reload-data-files (it&apos;s the two yellow arrows at the top of the Scenario Controller), then <b>Init</b> and <b>Play</b> again.
Chances are, you&apos;ll have to do some view re-arranging to see of this information - observe that the vessel monitor rescales to suit the available space.
<br/>
If the scenario is still running, every now and then the fisherman will change course - and you&apos;ll see the course change in the vessel monitor.  Yes, it&apos;s quite a boring vessel to watch.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Run on to the end of the scenario">
      <description>
         As you&apos;ll remember, we created an observer to stop the scenario after 24 hours.  Eventually, the scenario will stop stepping forwards, and the Scenario Controller will show why the scenario stopped.  Once the scenario does finish, ASSET will produce the track plot we requested.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
