<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Quick run-through">
	<intro>
		<description>
			These few steps will familiarise you with the ASSET user interface and general processes involved with creating anCheck you have some datanning a simulation.  TIn an earlier cheat sheet you should have created an empty project, and in there you provided a link to the sample ASSET data. prove a worthwhile foundation for you subsequently creating custom scenarios
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Checking you have some data">
		<description>
			In an earlier cheat sheet you should have created an empty project and linked in the sample ASSET data.  If you didn&apos;t, then frankly you&apos;re bugger - so if I was you I&apos;d go back and do it right now.cription>
	</item>
 <item
       title="ASSET data files">
    <description>
       ASSET breaks down thASSET breaks down the information required to run through a sOpen a scenario fileeparate file types: <b>ScenaRight, let&apos;s start off with a scenario file.  Double-click on the <b>ForceProt.asset</b> data file in the <b>AssetData</b> folder of your navigator.  It will open in the central editor pane.  ASSET&apos;s xml editor uses a two-tab construct.  At the foot of the editor pane you&apos;ll see two tabs, one named &lt;i&gt;Design&lt;/i&gt; and the other named &lt;i&gt;Source&lt;/i&gt;.  The Design tab is a tree-oriented editor that gives you an overview of your scenario, the Source tab lets you get right down in the weeds.<br/>
In the Design view, you&apos;ll see that the top-level element in our data is the tree, and this contains child elements that specify the time-step, the environment used for the simulation, and the participants in the simulation.  Open the participants element and you&apos;ll see it contains three surface vessels and a single ssk.  Open the first surface vessel and you&apos;ll see it&apos;s called HVU.  Feel free to browse through theapos;s start off wi
      <subitem
            label="&lt;b&gt;ASSET&apos;s xml editor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br/&gt;">
      </subitem>th a scenario file.  Double-click on the <b>ForceProt.asset</b> data file in the <b>AssetData</b> folder of your navigator.  It will open in the central editor pane.  ASSET&apos;s xml editor uses a two-tab construct.  At the foot of the editor pane you&apos;ll see two tabs, one named &lt;i&gt;Design&lt;/i&gt; and the other named &lt;i&gt;Source&lt;/i&gt;.  The Design tab is a tree-oriented editor that gives you an overview of your scenario, the Source tab lets you get right down in the weeds.apos;s start off wi
      <subitem
            label="ASSET&apos;s xml editor">
      </subitem>th aes describe what&apos;s to be simulated, and <b>Control</b> files direct ASSET in how to run the simulation.  Whilst both types of file contain data stored in the textual &lt;i&gt;xml&lt;/i&gt; data format, the ASSET working practice is that scenario files have the <b>.asset</b> file suffix (to aid you organise your data).s down the information required to run through a simulation into two separate file types: <b>Scenario</b> files describe what&apos;s to be simulated, and <b>Control</b> files direct ASSET in how to run the simulation.  Whilst both types of file contain data stored in the textual &lt;i&gt;xml&lt;/i&gt; data format, the ASSET working practice is that scenario files have the <b>.asset</b> file suffix.s down the information required to run through a simulation into two separate file types: <b>Scenario</b> files describe what&apos;s to be simulated, and <b>Control</b> files direct ASSET in how to run the simulation.s down the information required to run through a simulation into two separate file types: <b>scenario</b> file describe what&apos;s to be simulated, and <b>control</b> files direct ASSET in how to run the simulation.on required to run through a simulation into two separate file types: <b>scenario</b> file describe what&amp;apos;s to be simulated, and <b>control</b> files direct ASSET in how to run the simulation.
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="View a scenario file">
    <description>
       <b>Body</b>
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="View a control file">
    <description>
       <b>Body</b>
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="Load the data">
    <description>
       <b>Body</b>
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="Run the scenario">
    <description>
       <b>Body</b>
    </description>
 </item>
 <item
       title="Watch the scenario">
    <description>
       <b>Body</b>
    </description>
 </item>

</cheatsheet>
