<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Run multi-participant scenario">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Now, we&apos;re going to work on a more complex problem - asking ASSET to generate multiple instances of our Fishing vessel.  We do this by including instructions in the control file regarding which elements of the scenario to change, and how to change them.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="View the scenario">
      <description>
         Start off by re-opening the scenario file we&apos;ve been working with - the one that contains a single fishing vessel.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Decide what to change">
      <description>
         Right, the scenario&apos;s open. What shall we change?  I know, let&apos;s get ASSET to create 100 fishing vessels, all with different start locations, plus with different search speeds.<br/>Fortunately there&apos;s a convenience function for changing the initial location of generated participants, but we have to do a little more computer jiggery-pokery to specify the speed attribute.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Create duplicate control file">
      <description>
         Now, we don&apos;t want to overwrite our existing control file, so copy/paste our existing <b>trial1.xml</b> using either the keyboard or the menus.  Name the new control file <b>trial_multi_part.xml</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
 <item
         title="Open the scenario controller">
      <description>
         Next, double-click on our new control file to open it in the xml editor.  Next, open the ScenarioController element and give it a <b>ScenarioGenerator</b> child element. It&apos;s this element that handles generation of both multiple participants and multiple scenarios.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Add participant generation code">
      <description>
         Next, add a <b>MultiParticipantGenerator</b> element to the <b>ScenarioGenerator</b>.<br/>
Next, add a <b>ParticipantVariance</b> element to this. A <b>ParticipantVariance</b> describes the variances to apply to a single participant - specified using the participant name.
      </description>
   </item>
<item
         title="Add specification for multi participant generation">
      <description>
        So, set the <b>name</b> attribute of the ParticipantVariance to Fisher One (or whatever you named the fishing vessel), and set the number to 100 - to say we want 100 of them.  Next, we&apos;ll set the initial locations, so add a <b>ParticipantLocation</b> element to this.  Give this an area of 50 to 51 degs North, and -8 to -9 degs West..
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Add the Wander speed variance">
      <description>
         Next we&apos;re going to specify how to vary the Wander speed. Start by adding a <b>Variance</b> element to the <b>ParticipantVariance</b> for Fisher One.  Next, right-click on the <b>LocationArea</b> element and select <b>Replace with</b> an <b>Attribute</b> element.  Name this element as &apos;Vary the wander speed&apos;.  Next. specify that we&apos;re going to vary the attribute through a <b>Range</b> of values from 2 to 10, and use the name <b>Value</b>.  We also need to tell the Variance element what it&apos;s going to apply to, so put <b>/Wander/Speed</b> in the id field.  This phrase follows the XPath regular expression standard - but essentially it just matches XML Element names, with single slashes showing the parent/child relationship, and double-slashes matching against any number of parent/child tiers.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Bring on the referee">
      <description>
         Now that we&apos;ve got lots of fishermen, we&apos;re going to get ASSET to help us see how effectively the frigate searches the area.  We can do this by adding a <b>RemoveDetectedObserver</b> to the <b>ObserverList</b>.  Now, name this as <b>Ditch detected fishermen</b>.  We need to tell this observer which type of vessel to track the detections of (the <b>Watch</b> type), and also what types of participant that vessel is looking for (the <b>Target</b>).  So, set the Target to <b>GREEN</b> and the Watch to <b>BLUE</b>.  Now, <b>RemoveDetectedObserver</b> is an observer that is capable of providing a continuous readout of of its performance measure.  You&apos;ll be using the <b>Live Data</b> to track this.
      </description>
   </item>
      <item
         title="Load the new controller file">
      <description>
         Now, save our new control file, and drag it from the <b>Navigator</b> to the <b>Scenario Controller</b> view.  As you drop it, you should see the current tab switch to <b>Multiple Scenarios</b>.  This panel allows a series of scenarios to be run.   Start off by clicking on <b>Generate</b>.  ASSET will now go away and generate multiple participants and scenarios as necessary, finally enabling the <b>Run</b> button.  Note, once the generate is complete, you&apos;ll see that the table of scenarios now also contains a column titled <b>Ditch detected fisherman</b>.  To keep track of this live data, select <b>Live Data</b> from the Show/View menu - then click on the <b>Ditch detected fisherman</b> cell in the <b>Scenario Controller</b> window (to tell the Live Data window what to watch).
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Inspect the generated scenario">
      <description>
         Before we run the scenario, let&apos;s have a look at what ASSET has generated.  In the <b>Navigator</b> window, have a look in the <b>Results</b> folder.  You&apos;ll see a copy of the control file, and a folder called <b>1</b>.  ASSET numbers the generated scenarios, so you can see it&apos;s just created the one.  Open this folder and you&apos;ll see a single file titled <b>Cheat sheet scenario.xml</b>.  Double-click to open it.  Inside this scenario you&apos;ll see that there are now 100 surface participants, each with a unique vessel name.  Have a look at their Wander behaviours, and you&apos;ll see that there are a range of speeds specified.  <b>Note</b>, the random numbers have lots of decimal places, the <b>format</b> attribute of the <b>Variance</b> element we used allows us to specify the number of decimal places used.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Re-run the scenario">
      <description>
         Ok, back to the scenario.  Click on <b>Run</b>, and the scenario will run through.  It will take a little longer than before, since it&apos;s now progressing 100 fishermen, not one.  As the scenario plays through, to start with your <b>Live Data</b> window will not show any data, but as the blue platform starts detecting green, entries will start to appear on the graph.  After about 10 hours you&apos;ll see that the graph starts to level off,
         
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Inspect a results output">
      <description>
         Once the scenario is complete, you can go into the <b>results</b> folder in the Navigator and you&apos;ll see the new output files.  If you open the <b>png</b>, you&apos;ll see the very cluttered output - with lots of vessel tracks.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Watch things unfold in Debrief">
      <description>
         Now that there are loads of participants in there, it&apos;s a little more interesting to watch in Debrief.  Click on <b>Generate</b> again to reset the scenario. Now, either switch to your existing Debrief plot viewer tab, or open another by clicking on the Scenario Controller&apos;s globe toolbar icon.  Debrief will be empty when it first opens.  Now click on the <b>Name</b> of the current scenario in the Scenario Controller view, and Debrief will open a view of the scenario, with all of those fishermen.
<br/>
Now, if you click on <b>Run</b> you&apos;ll see of the busy fishermen set off doing their business - being removed from the simulation as they&apos;re detected by the Blue frigate.  What fun!
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
