<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Generate a scenario">
   <intro>
      <description>
         <b>In this part of the tutorial you are going to create a new, empty scenario file - then populate it with sample data.</b>
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Select location for new scenario">
      <description>
         Some thinking first.  Have a look in your navigator view, and decide on a location for your new scenario file.  It isn&apos;t all that tidy to put it into the existing AssetData sample data folder, so you could create a new folder in the root of your project (by right-clicking on the root folder and selecting &apos;New Folder&apos;.  The new folder could be called &apos;trials&apos;, for example.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Create empty scenario file">
      <description>
         Now that you know where to put the new scenario, right click on the parent folder and select <b>New \ Other...</b>.  From the tree of available wizards, select &apos;XML&apos; from the &apos;XML&apos; folder. Now press &apos;Next&apos;.  On the next page of the wizard, provide a filename for the new scenario - how about <b>trial1.asset</b>.  On the next page, select  <b>Create XML file from an XML schema file</b>.  Obviously, now Asset wants to know which schema (model definition) file to use, so select <b>Select file from workspace</b> and browse to <b>ASSET.XSD</b> in your sample data folder.  On the next page you must specify a root element, select &apos;Scenario&apos; - and you&apos;re done.  The file will then open.
         
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Admire the editor">
      <description>
         Your new scenario will probably open in <b>Source</b> view.  This is ok fo geeks, but you may find it easier to use the tree oriented view.  Switch to this by clicking on the <b>Design</b> tab at the foot of the editor pane.  

Now your in the graphic view, experiment with expanding the <b>Scenario</b>.  

By the way, if you look at ASSET&apos;s <b>Outline</b> view (or click the arrow below) you&apos;ll see an outline view of the current sceanrio.

ASSET&apos;s Properties view is also useful when working with scenario files.  Open the properties view by selecting Window/Show View/Properties.  Now, you are able to edit the attributes for any element selected in the editor view.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.eclipse.ui.views.ContentOutline)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Edit scenario properties">
      <description>
         Youve got big dreams? You want fame? Well, fame costs.  And right here is where you start paying in sweat.

Well, not quite, but you do have to start typing now.  So, open the Scenario element, and give the scenario a name &apos;Cheat sheet scenario&apos;.  If you switch to the properties view you&apos;ll see the other attributes needed: <b>Created</b> and <b>StartTime</b>. ASSET expects dates in the ISO 8601 date standard: <b>2010-01-12T12:13:14Z</b>.  Put in today&apos;s date as the created attribute, and any old date as the StartTime attribute.

Next, specify how far in time the scenario should step forward (<b>StepTime</b>). Have a go at one minute: <b>Minutes</b> are the <b>Unit</b> and 1 is the <b>Value</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Specify Environment">
      <description>
         Now we have to give the scenario an environment.  Do this by right-clicking on the <b>Scenario</b> and selecting <b>Add child</b> / <b>Environment</b>.  Also, give it a name - how about <b>Atlantic Summer</b>.  Play with the sea state and atmospheric attenuation if you wish.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Add simple participant">
      <description>
         Next, we have to put something into the scenario.  Right-click on
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Edit participant properties">
      <description>
         <b>Body</b>
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Load actual sample dataset">
      <description>
         <b>Body</b>
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
