<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Configuring ASSET">
   <intro>
      <description>
         <b>ASSET uses a workspace to contain your data.  Data in this workspace is stored in Project folders.  So you need to create a folder.  This is also a convenient time to integrate some sample data and check that you have a valid XML editor</b>
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Open the navigator">
      <description>
         The <b>Navigator</b> window is your view of your data files.  It should be visible at the top-left of ASSET.  If it isn&apos;t open it via Window/Show View/Navigator, or by using &apos;Click to perform&apos; below.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.eclipse.ui.views.ResourceNavigator)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Check you have a project">
      <description>
         When first opened, workspaces are typically empty. You create a project that contains either your data files, or a number of links to existing data.  So, have a look in your Navigator and see if there are any folders (projects) listed there.
      </description>
   </item>
	<item
       dialog="true"
       skip="true"
       title="Create a &apos;General&apos; project">
		<description>If your navigator is empty, then yes, you need to create a project. Right-click in the Navigator view, and select &apos;Project...&apos; from the &apos;New&apos; sub-menu.  The New Project wizard will open. From the &apos;General&apos; folder, select Project, and then press &apos;Next&apos;. Now just enter a name for your project (this could be your name or the name of the current simulation exercise). Lastly press the &apos;Finish&apos; button, and you will see the new project in your workspace.  Or use the &apos;Click to run&apos; link below to quickly open the New project window.
		</description>
  <command
        required="false"
        serialization="org.eclipse.ui.newWizard(newWizardId=org.eclipse.ui.wizards.new.project)"/>
	</item>
	
   <item
         title="Check you have an XML editor">
      <description>
         <b>ASSET uses data files that adhere to the XML data standard. XML is easily read and manipulated by computers, but can be a little verbose and fiddly when edited by humans. That&apos;s why we use an XML Editor that hides some of the fiddly details</b><br/>
ASSET is based on the Eclipse platform, which includes its own rudimentary xml editor. Check this is present by expanding the sample data folder in your Navigator. Now right-click on an xml file.  In the &quot;Open With&quot; sub-menu you should see &quot;XML Editor&quot;, this confirms the xml editor is present and working.  If you don&apos;t see the XML Editor entry, please contact the mainainer - since it appears your installation is invalid.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
