<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet
      title="Groom sensor data">
   <intro>
      <description>
         This cheat sheet is going to work through creating preparing the ownship sensor data ready for production of TMA tracks.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Load datafiles">
      <description>
         We&apos;re using new datafiles for this step, so double-click on <b>nonsuch.rep</b> in the Navigator to load ownship track (and select <b>DR</b> mode when asked).  Perform a Fit to Window once loaded to have a look at the track. Next, drag in <b>sensor.dsf</b>.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.eclipse.ui.views.ResourceNavigator)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Make sensor data visible">
      <description>
         To keep the plot tidy, sensor data is not shown by default when loaded.  Expand <b>Track:NONSUCH</b> in the <b>Layer Manager</b>, then select <b>Sensor:Sensor_A (52 items)</b>. Once the Sensor A sensor data is selected, click on the tick icon in the toolbar at top of the Layer Manager view, to make the sensor data visible.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Set array offset">
      <description>
         As you&apos;ll see, the sensor data is ambiguous as produced by a towed array.  Currently Debrief is plotting the sensor cuts against the attack datum of the platform, but we need to apply an offset for this sensor (451m in this case).  So, select <b>Sensor:SENSOR_A</b> in the <b>Layer Manager</b>, then open the <b>Properties Window</b> (the click to perform button below will also open it).  In the Properties Window you&apos;ll see the <b>SensorOffset</b> attribute, enter -451 metres in this field, click on the Plot, and you&apos;ll see the bearings jump to reflect the change.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.views.showView(org.eclipse.ui.views.showView.viewId=org.eclipse.ui.views.PropertySheet)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/GroomingTrackData.html#ResamplingData"
         skip="true"
         title="Reduce data density">
      <description>
         Whilst it isn&apos;t necessary for this exercise, Debrief does allow you to reduce the density of the sensor data.  If you right-click on <b>Sensor:SENSOR_A</b>, then navigate down into the <b>SENSOR_A</b> sub-menu you will see a <b>Visible Frequency</b> option. Using one of these options will pass through sensor data and hide sensor observations between the specified frequency.  The sensor cuts remain available, and can be made visible again by selecting a smaller visible frequency.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
