<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../contentFile.xsd"
 title="Viewing the data">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Let's understand the data we've got, before we start playing with it
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
      title="View the ownship track">
      <description>         
         When you view the tutoral plot you will see an ownship track.  Use the Debrief Time Controller to 
         familiarise yourself with the general motion of the OWNSHIP track.  You'll see that it starts in the 
         North-East of the area, then travels quite slowly at 2.5 knots, with two straight legs.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="View the sensor data">
      <description>         
         The identification of straight legs is pivotal to the SATC process, since they greatly constrain
         the possible solution combinations.
         <br/>
         Just as with manual TMA, the best practice for this process is to color the sensor cuts according
         to the leg they're contained in.  If you make the sensor data visible for the Ownship track, you'll see 
         that the first and second legs have been coloured in green and purple, respectively. Between each leg, a
         few cuts have been left red, to provide time for the target to make alterations.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Mark the final target leg">
      <description>         
         Whilst the first two target legs have been coloured, the last one hasn't. So, expand the sensor data
         in the Layer Manager, and select the sensor cuts from <b>100112 124230</b> until the end of the
         dataset, at <b>100112 140000</b>.  Now use the <b>Properties</b> view to change the color of these cuts to <b>Yellow</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/satc.html#satc_intro"
      title="Create the scenario">
      <description>
         The most significant block of information in generating a solution is the bearing data.  So, the 
         first step is to specify bearing data.  We are going to use all of the Ownship sensor data for this
         solution, so right-click on the <b>Sensor:Plan (145 items)</b> sensor, and select <b>Semi Auto TMA</b> / 
         <b>Create new scenario from these cuts</b>.
         <br/>As with the previous tutorial, you will see the new scenario appear in the layer manager, and the 
         <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view will open.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
