<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../contentFile.xsd"
 title="Playing with legs">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Once we&apos;re confident in the set of target legs we can move on to capture
         more of the analyst&apos;s knowledge and refine the target track.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
      title="Introduce speed constraint">
      <description>We did not have target track data for this hypothetical engagement, but we did
         have a record of the target&apos;s speed. We will now add it to our scenario.</description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Add Speed constraint">
      <description>
         There are a number of ways to add a speed constraint:
        <br/><b>1.</b> At the per-leg level, we can expand a <b>Straight Leg Forecast</b> and enter min/max/estimate values for course or speed for each leg.
        <br/><b>2.</b> We can apply a speed constraint to the whole engagement. 
        <br/>To do the latter:
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, right-click on the <b>Bearing Data</b> item and select <b>Add speed forecast for period covered by [Selected Legs]</b>. 
        <br/><b>2.</b> When the <b>New contribution</b> dialog box opens, enter <b>Overall speed</b> as the name of this contribution.
        <br/><b>3.</b> Click on <b>Ok</b> and the new contribution will appear in the listing in the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Specify speed constraint">
      <description>
         The exercise observer recorded that the target was doing around 9 knots during the whole exercise, so we must enter this constraint to allow for speed keeping errors:
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view, expand the <b>Speed Forecast</b> control
        <br/><b>2.</b> Enter a <b>minimum speed</b> of <b>8 knots</b>
        <br/><b>3.</b> Enter a <b>maximum speed</b> of <b>10 knots</b>
        <br/><b>4.</b> Enter an <b>(optional) estimate</b> of <b>9 knots</b>
        <br/><b>5.</b> Click on the <b>Calculate Solution</b> button. 
        <br/>In the <b>Performance</b> tab, you will see the effectiveness of both the <b>Bearing Data</b> and the <b>Overall speed</b> estimates. The bars are shaded according to the respective color-coded constraint.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Generate manual TMA solution">
      <description>
         We will now use this information to develop a manual TMA solution. 
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, right-click on the <b>TMA solution</b> and select <b>Convert to Composite Track (legs)</b>.
        <br/>A manual solution (<b>Track:121200.00_0</b>) will now appear in the <b>Outline</b> view, and the auto TMA solution will be hidden.
        <br/>Mark the new solution as a secondary track by:
        <br/><b>2.</b> Left-clicking to select it in the <b>Outline</b> view 
        <br/><b>3.</b> Click on the <b>2</b> in the <b>Outline</b> view toolbar.
         We are now ready to manually adjust the solution.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Tune manual TMA solution">
      <description>
         To manually tune the TMA solution:
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> vView, ensure the track is selected
        <br/><b>2.</b> Click on the <b>Drag Track Segment</b> button on the main application toolbar and the Bearing Residuals window will open.
        <br/><b>Note:</b> if the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> window is empty, open the <b>Track Tote View</b> and check that your primary track is <b>Ownship</b> and your secondary track is <b>121200.00_0</b>. If they are not, assign these accordingly in the <b>Outline</b> view.
        <br/>Alternatively, if the ownship sensor cuts are not visible, you will need to clear the <b>Only draw dots for visible sensor points</b> button in the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> view toolbar.
        <br/><b>3.</b> In the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> view, click on the <b>Shear</b> button.
        <br/><b>4.</b> In the plot area, begin dragging track segments to minimise the bearing errors.
        <br/>Don&apos;t worry if your track segment dragging results in a mangled solution, you can delete the manual track from the <b>Outline</b> view and generate a new one from your existing solution.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Merge track segments">
      <description>
         When you are happy with your solution, you can merge the separate track segments into a formal track.
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, expand your manual TMA solution
        <br/><b>2.</b> Right-click on the <b>Track Segments (5 items)</b> and select <b>Merge all track segments from the popup list</b>.
        <br/>You now have a track for the subject vessel that can be used for further analysis.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Mark your answers">
      <description>
         To check how well you did:
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, select <b>Track:Subject</b>
        <br/><b>2.</b> Click on <b>Reveal Selected Items</b> (make visible)
        <br/>This is the actual <b>Truth Track</b>; so, how does it compare with your track?
        <br/>If you prefer a more quantitative score, produce an <b>XY Plot</b> of the range between your solution and the truth track:
        <br/><b>1.</b> Ctrl-click on both tracks to select them.
        <br/><b>2.</b> Right-click and select <b>View XY Plot</b>
        <br/><b>3.</b> In the <b>View time-variable plot</b> dialog, select <b>Range</b>
        <br/><b>4.</b> Click on <b>Ok</b>.
        <br/>You can now see a plot of how well you did.
        <br/> Ideally, you should be able to achieve an accuracy of around 200 yds, which is not bad when you are using sensor data at around 20000 yds.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
