<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../contentFile.xsd"
 title="Playing with legs">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Once we&apos;re confident in the set of target legs we can move on to capture
         more of the analyst&apos;s knowledge and refine the target track.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
      title="Introduce speed constraint">
      <description>         
      	For this hypothetical engagement, whilst we didn&apos;t have target track data, we 
      	did have a record of target speed.  We&apos;re going to add it here. 
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Add Speed constraint">
      <description>         
      	We can add a speed constraint in a number of ways. At the per-leg level we can expand a
      	<b>Straight Leg Forecast</b> and enter min/max/estimate values for course or speed for each leg.
      	<br/>
      	Alternatively we can apply a speed constraint to the whole engagement.  Do this by right-clicking 
      	on the <b>Bearing Data</b> item in the Outline view and selecting 
      	<b>Add speed forecast for period covered by [Selected Legs]</b>.  When the popup box 
      	opens, enter <b>Overall speed</b> to name the contribution.
      	<br/>
      	As the contribution gets added you will see the target solution disappear, since its no longer valid.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Specify speed constraint">
      <description>         
         Now we must enter the actual constraint in the <b>Speed Forecast</b> control
         in the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view.  The exercise observer recorded that the target was doing
         around 9 knots during the whole exercise.  So, to allow for speed keeping errors, enter
         a minimum speed of 8 knots, a maximum speed of 10 knots, and an (optional) estimate of 9 knots.
         <br/>
         Then re-run the <b>Calculate Solution</b> button. In the <b>Performance</b> tab you will see the effectiveness
         of both the <b>Bearing Data</b> and the <b>Overall speed</b> estimates.  The bars are shaded according to
         the respective color-coded constraint.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Generate manual TMA solution">
      <description>         
      	As previously we finish off the TMA generation process by developing a manual TMA solution.  Right-click
      	on the TMA solution in the <b>Outline</b> view, and select <b>Convert to Composite Track (legs)</b>.
      	<br/>
      	A manual solution will now appear in the <b>Outline</b> view, and the auto TMA solution will be hidden.  Mark
      	the new solution as a <b>Secondary</b> track by selecting it in the <b>Outline</b> view then clicking on
      	the <b>2</b> in the <b>Outline</b> view toolbar.
      	<br/>
      	Were now ready to manually adjust the solution.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Tune manual TMA solution">
      <description>         
      	Start manually tuning the TMA solution by clicking on the <b>Drag Track Segment</b> mouse mode button on the main
      	application toolbar. As you click on it, the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> window will open.  
      	<br/>
      	If the Bearing Residuals window is empty, open the <b>Track Tote</b> and double-check that your 
      	primary track <b>Ownship</b> and secondary track <b>121200.00_0</b> are assigned.
      	<br/>
      	Alternatively, if the ownship sensor cuts are not visible, you will need to clear the 
      	<b>Only draw dots for visible sensor points</b> check button in the <b>Bearing Residuals</b>
      	view toolbar.
      	<br/>
      	Now select <b>Shear</b> drag mode in the <b>Bearing Residuals</b> window and start dragging track segments
      	to minimise the bearing errors.
      	<br/>
      	Don&apos;t worry if your track segment dragging results in a mangled solution, you can just just delete the manual track from
      	the <b>Outline</b> view and generate a new one from your existing solution.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Merge track segments">
      <description>         
      	When you are finally happy with your solution its time to merge the separate track segments into a formal track. 
      	<br/>
      	To do this, you need to expand your manual TMA solution in the <b>Outline</b> view, then right-click 
      	on the <b>Track Segments (5)</b> item.  From the popup list, select <b>Merge all track segments</b>.
      	<br/>
      	You now have a track for the subject vessel that you can use for your further analysis.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Mark your answers">
      <description>         
      	What? You want to know how well you did? 
      	<br/>
      	Simple, the <b>truth</b> track for the problem is the <b>Subject</b> track in the <b>Outline</b> view.  
      	Just make it visible and compare how your solution looks against it. 
      	<br/>
      	If you&apos;d like a more quantitative score, produce an XY Plot of range between your solution and the truth
      	track.  You should be able to achieve an accuracy of around 200 yds - not bad when we&apos;re using sensor
      	data at around 20000 yds.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
