<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../contentFile.xsd"
 title="Grooming the data">
   <intro>
      <description>
         Let&apos;s understand the data we&apos;ve got, before we start manipulating it.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
   	title="Understanding our data">
		<description>To understand what is occurring here, use the Debrief <b>Time Controller</b> and the
			<b>Track Tote</b> to familiarise yourself with the general motion of the <b>OWNSHIP</b> track. As you
			do, you will see that the vessel starts in the North-East of the plot, then travels
			quite slowly at 2.5 knots, with two straight legs.</description>
   </item>
   <item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/satc.html#satc_intro"
      title="Create the scenario">
   	<description>
   		The most significant block of information in generating a solution is the bearing data itself, but we need to identify this as such to Debrief. 
   		<br/>In this scenario, we will use all of the Ownship sensor data:
   		<br/><b>1.</b> Left-click on the drop-down arrow next to <b>Track:Ownship</b>
   		<br/><b>2.</b> Left-click on <b>Sensors</b> to expand it.
   		<br/><b>3.</b> Select <b>Sensor:Plain (145 items)</b>, right-click and select <b>Semi Auto TMA</b> > <b>Create new scenario from these bearings</b>.
   		<br/>As with the previous tutorial, you will see the new scenario (called <b>121200.00</b>) appear in the <b>Outline</b> view, and the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view will open with just one contribution.
   	</description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Intro to Zig Detection">
   	<description>
   		Though <b>SATC's Manoeuvre Detection Aid</b> is capable of detecting target zigs, the algorithm can only reliably detect target zigs during an ownship straight leg (the geometry is just too chaotic during an ownship turn), so the actual process involves two steps:
   		<br/><b>1.</b> Detecting ownship legs
   		<br/><b>2.</b> Detecting target zigs during those straight legs.
   		Despite this, the algorithm does make a rough and ready attempt at determining if there is a target zig somewhere during an ownship turn by forecasting the bearing rate in the second leg. If the post-turn bearing rate does not match that produced in a passive ranging calculation, then a turn is assumed. However, as the algorithm won&apos;t know when the target turn occured during the ownship turn, it interprets the whole ownship turn as the period of the target turn.
   	</description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Generate the target legs">
   	<description>
   		As mentioned in the previous step, the process begins with determining the ownship legs. Though this is easily discernable to the human eye, it is less so for a computer, and the main information source for target zig detection is the bearing data.
   		<br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view, expand the <b>Bearing Measurement - Bearing data</b> section. Near the bottom of the control, you will find the <b>MDA</b> (Manoeuvre Detection Algorithm) section.
   		<br/><b>2.</b> Click on <b>1. Slice O/S legs</b> to slice the ownship legs. 
   		<br/><b>3.</b> Now, take a look at the <b>Ownship &amp; Target Legs</b> graph at the bottom of the screen to judge the effectiveness of the slices.
   		<br/>When SATC slices the legs, it shades each leg in blue, with transparent gaps between the legs. Ownship legs are labelled with text labels at the top of the chart.
   		<br/>For this dataset, when run with <b>Low</b> precision, the algorithm thinks there is just one ownship leg. 
   		<br/>However, based on the displayed graph of ownship course and speed against time, this is clearly incorrect; it&apos;s just that the ownship turns and speed changes are too subtle for the turn detector. 
   		<br/><b>4.</b> So, change the <b>SATC precision</b> value to <b>Medium</b> or <b>High</b> using the drop-down list at the top of the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view.
   		<br/><b>5.</b> Click on <b>1. Slice O/S legs</b> again. You will probably find that <b>Medium</b> precision gives the best result.
   		<br/>Once you are happy with the ownship legs:
   		<br/><b>6.</b> Click on <b>2. Slice Tgt legs</b> and the MDA algorithm will produce a series of legs for you. 
   		<br/>On my machine, the algorithm produces four target legs. The algorithm-spotted target turns part-way through ownship legs 1 and 2, and it also assumes a target turn somewhere during the ownship turn from leg 1 to leg 2.
   	</description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Groom the target legs">
   	<description>
   		Let&apos;s look at what the algorithm produces from these target legs:
   		<br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>Calculate Solution</b>; after a few seconds, the algorithm produces a target track shown on the plot.
   		<br/>Looking at the target track, you should see that the very short target leg 3 is quite similar to leg 2. Switching back to the <b>Ownship &amp; Target Legs</b> graph, you can see that legs 2 and 3 are split by the suspected target zig during the ownship turn. We can guess that the target zig early in ownship leg 2 has mistakenly caused the algorithm to predict a target turn during the ownship turn.
   		<br/>We must therefore merge target legs 2 and 3: 
   		<br/><b>2.</b> Open <b>Scenario (121200.00)</b> in the <b>Outline</b> view and you will see the <b>bearing data</b> listed, followed by our four target legs (<b>Tgt-x</b>).
   		<br/><b>3.</b> Ctrl-click on legs <b>Tgt-2</b> and <b>Tgt-3</b> to select them
   		<br/><b>4.</b> Right-click on either one and select <b>Merge Straight Leg Forecasts</b>. 
   		<br/>As soon as you do this, the target legs will merge, the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view will update, and the calculated solution will disappear from the plot because it is no longer valid.
   		<br/><b>5.</b> Click on the <b>Calculate Solutions</b> button to rerun the solution. You will see that the new solution looks quite good.
   	</description>
   </item>
 </cheatsheet>
