<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../contentFile.xsd" title="Create scenario">
   <intro>
      <description>Debrief uses the term <b>scenario</b> to describe the collection of data that is
         collated in order for SATC to produce an optimal solution. Let&apos;s create our first
         scenario now.</description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Browse to the sensor data">
      <description> We will use all of the ownship sensor data to create our scenario:
        <br/><b>1.</b> Open the <b>Outline</b> view
        <br/><b>2.</b> Open <b>Track:OWNSHIP</b>.
        <br/><b>3.</b> The ownship track has a <b>Sensors (1 items)</b> object; open
         this and you will see the single block of sensor data called <b>Sensor:Plain (11 items)</b>.
        <br/><b>4.</b> Right-click on it and select <b>SemiAuto TMA</b> ><b> Create new scenario from these bearings</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Create scenario based upon cuts">
      <description> A new item with the name <b>121213.14</b> is created in the <b>Outline</b> view
         (the item name is auto-selected from the Date-Time-Group (DTG) of the first item in the
         bearing data).
        <br/>You will also see that the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view has opened. This view
         is used to create and manage your scenario data. If you haven&apos;t read about the SATC user
         interface via the help page earlier on, please read it now<i>NoPrint</i> by clicking the link below<i>NoPrint</i>. </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.help.displayHelp(href=/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/satc.html#satc_ui)"/>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Change scenario name">
      <description>As nice as it is to try and remember a new set of telephone numbers every time
         you create a new scenario, it makes sense to rename the scenario to something more
         meaningful:
        <br/><b>1.</b> Select this scenario in the <b>Outline</b> view
        <br/><b>2.</b> In the <b>Properties</b> view (<b>Windows</b> >
         <b>Show View</b> > <b>Properties</b>, if it isn&apos;t visible) change the <b>Name</b> value to <b>Single Leg</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
    <item
      title="Understand the contributions window">
       <description>
          In the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view, you can see a single <b>Bearing Measurement - Bearing Data</b> item listed in the <b>Analyst Contributions</b> section.
         <br/>This is the bearing data that will be used to inform all of the subsequent contributions.
       </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Viewing the bearing measurement contributions">
      <description> The <b>Bearing Measurement Contribution</b> is the set of bearings that represent the
         unknown target track. You can see that the contribution has an estimated <b>error</b> value of
         <b>+/- 3 degs</b>, so the algorithm will only offer solutions that are within 3 degrees
         of these bearing measurements.
        <br/>To view these measurements:
        <br/><b>1.</b> Select the track <b>Single Leg</b> in
         the <b>Outline</b> view.
        <br/><b>2.</b> In the <b>Properties</b> view, select the <b>ShowLocationConstraints</b> item.
        <br/><b>3.</b> In the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view, click on the <b>Calculate Solution</b> button.
        <br/>A set of "pie-slices" will now appear on the plot showing the allowable 3-degree error on each
         bearing measurement.
        <br/><b>4.</b> Still in the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view, expand the <b>Bearing
         Measurement - Bearing Data</b> contribution and you will see that it is possible to change the
         error value on this bearing data by moving the slider. As you move and release the slider
         you will see the pie slices expand and contract (you may need to click on the <b>Auto-Recalc
         of Constraints</b> button in the <b>Preferences</b> area to initiate this).
        <br/><b>Note:</b> The <b>Auto-Recalc of
         Constraints</b> is a two-state button that is normally depressed. But, if you have a complex
         scenario that takes some time to update, you may wish to uncheck this button so the screen doesn&apos;t refresh while you are interactively adjusting any contributions.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Get ready to specify a target leg">
      <description><br/><b>Note:</b> in this sample data, the imported bearings have a maximum range of 12,000
         yards (yds). In the absence of a range estimate, SATC will restrict them to 30k yds to stop
         your PC doing the &apos;Ferranti Reset&apos;.
        <br/>Also, before we continue, Debrief must be reset to a
         predictable state:
        <br/><b>1.</b> Restore the <b>Analyst Contribution</b> to 3 degrees In the <b>Properties</b>
         view, deselect the <b>ShowLocationConstraints</b> (so it shows <b>No</b>).</description>
   </item>
   <item title="Specify a target leg">
      <description> It is possible that your deep analysis skills have led you to believe that all of
         these cuts relate to a single leg of target data where the target maintains course and
         speed through the period of interest - this is useful information to the TMA algorithms.
        <br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, select <b>Track:Ownship</b> > <b>Sensors (1 items)</b>, and then right-click on
         <b>Sensor:Plain (11 items)</b>
        <br/><b>2.</b> From the drop-down menu, select <b>Semi Auto TMA</b> > <b>Add to Single Leg</b>
         > <b>New Straight Leg for period covered by [sensor cuts]</b>. When the <b>New contribution</b> dialog
         opens, name this contribution &apos;Leg limits&apos;.
        <br/><b>3.</b> Click on <b>Ok</b>.
        <br/><b>4.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, you will see <b>Single Leg (1 item)</b> has changed to <b>Single Leg (2 items)</b>.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
      title="Understanding the contributions">
      <description>So, now there are two contributions for this scenario:
        <br/><b>1.</b> a set of bearings
         through which a solution must travel
        <br/><b>2.</b> an indication that the target will have travelled on
         a single course and speed throughout the entire engagement.
        <br/>An observant analyst will have
         noticed that our two ownship turns have provided a valuable change in bearing rate -
         exactly what a TMA algorithm needs.
        <br/>So, now that we&apos;ve provided the TMA algorithm with some
         viable data, let&apos;s see it calculate a solution.</description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
