<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../contentFile.xsd" title="Generate a solution">
   <intro>
      <description>Now that we have provided background data to SATC, we can generate a solution.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item
         title="Calculate the solution">
      <description> Now we&apos;re going to generate the solution for this scenario. Before we do this:
         <br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Fit to Window</b> button to ensure you can see the ownship track and the rough
         area where the target should be.
         <br/><b>2.</b> Click on the <b>Calculate Solution</b> button.
         <br/>By default, the
         SATC is set to <b>Low</b> precision and uses relaxed constraints. The rather sparse bearing data
         and ownship maneuvers used in this scenario means that there aren&apos;t very many candidate
         solutions, and an answer will be generated within a second or so. When it has completed its
         calculations, a new track will appear on the plot.
         <br/>As you can see, the track is the
         color you specified for the bearing data in the <b>Bearing Import Wizard</b>.
         <br/>My computer
         returned a solution of <b>9.0 kts</b> on <b>269 degrees</b>. You can alter the precision setting as you
         require (to medium or high), but you must click on <b>Calculate Solution</b> each time you do.
         <br/>It is unlikely that you will get a better solution with this set of data, but you will
         notice that the <b>Performance</b> graph (below the <b>Maintain Contributions</b> view) processes more slowly
         as SATC homes in on a particular solution. You will see that the x-axis shows more cycles
         have been computed, and that each one moves more slowly.</description>
   </item>
   <item title="Marking your own homework">
      <description> The data we are using here is from a simulation tool, which means we have the
         actual target track to compare against:
         <br/><b>1.</b> Drag the <b>L1_SubjectTrack.rep</b> file into the plot area
         <br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Over the ground</b> as the import mode.
         <br/>The track will now appear on the plot
         as a solid red line.
         <br/>Now, compare the SATC solution with the actual target track. You will
         see that SATC is actually quite close, with a greater error near the start to the East because of the low bearing rate there; however, both tracks appear to be
         on a roughly parallel course.
         <br/>We now have an SATC-generated solution which is very close to
         the actual target track.</description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
