<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Configuring background data">
	<intro>
		<description>
			In addition to plotting your recorded vehicle data, Debrief is able
			to show a number of datasets in backdrop form.
			<br />
			In the past we offered the VPF vectored dataset and the
			 ETOPO-2 gridded bathymetry.  But, the shiny new Natural Earth
			 has effectively replaced both.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item		
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"	
		title="Getting hold of the Natural Earth dataset">
		<description>
			Debrief contains a very low resolution Natural Earth dataset, 
			sufficient to provide coastlines and country boundaries.
			<br/>
			You will probably wish to configure the higher resolution data,
			it will make your analysis plots much more attractive.  
			<br/>
			Your workplace may have a network copy of Natural Earth. If you have
			sufficient storage space on your machine (about 90Mb) you will get
			better performance by copying the data to your hard drive (IT policy
			permitting...).
			<br/>  
			But if you don&apos;t have access to a copy, you can get it 
			from the Internet (it&apos;s about 25Mb). Just click on the <b>Download zip</b> button on this site:
			<b>https://github.com/debrief/NaturalEarth</b>.  Once you have the zip-file, 
			just unzip it into a safe place on your hard drive.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Tell Debrief where to find your Natural Earth data">
		<description>
			Next we must tell Debrief where your data is. We do this 
			via the Preferences pane.
			<br/>
			So, select <b>Preferences</b> from the <b>Window</b> menu.
			Then open up the <b>Natural Earth</b> preferences page
			from the <b>Maritime Analysis</b> listing.
			Lastly, click on <b>Browse</b>
			to navigate to your unzipped Natural Earth folder.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#getting_vpf"
		title="How to configure VPF library datasets" skip="true">
		<description>
			Most users now find Natural Earth sufficient for background
			reference data.  If you wish to, you can learn about the legacy
			VPF and ETOPO in these next steps, but I&apos;d advice just skipping the steps
			and jumping forward to actual data.
			<br/>
			The steps to configure VPF are covered in Debrief&apos;s
			user manual. <i>NoPrint</i>If you wish to learn this at this stage, use the
			&apos;Question Mark&apos; help link alongside, else search for
			VPF
			in Debrief&apos;s online help at some future stage.<i>NoPrint</i>
			Here&apos;s a
			clue though, you go into the
			<b>Maritime Analysis</b>
			section of the Preferences. <br/> VPF is distributed as 4 CD-ROMS. If 
			you don&apos;t hold the CDs you can skip this step.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/etopo_data.html#etopo_install"
		title="How to configure ETOPO library data" skip="true">
		<description>
			<i>NoPrint</i>
			Use the help link to the side of this text to open the guidance on
			how to configure the location of the ETOPO data.
			<i>NoPrint</i>
			<i>Please read the relevant section of the Debrief user manual for how
				to specify use the Debrief/Preferences dialog the location of the ETOPO dataset.
				</i> 
				<br/>ETOPO is distributed as a ~200Mb data-file.  If 
			you don&apos;t hold the data-file you can skip this step.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
