<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Configuring background data">
	<intro>
		<description>In addition to plotting your recorded vehicle data, Debrief is able to show a
			number of datasets in backdrop form. In the past we offered the Vector Product Format
			(VPF) vectored dataset and the ETOPO-2 gridded bathymetry, but these have been
			superseded by the shiny new “<b>Natural Earth</b>”.</description>
	</intro>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Obtaining the Natural Earth dataset">
		<description>Debrief contains a small, low resolution subset of the “<b>Natural Earth</b>” dataset,
			sufficient to provide coastlines and country boundaries.<br/>However, you can make your
			analysis plots much more attractive by configuring higher resolution data.<br/>Your
			workplace may already have a network copy of “<b>Natural Earth</b>”; and, if your IT security
			policy permits it, and you have sufficient storage space on your machine, you will get
			better performance by copying the data to your hard drive.<br/>If you don&apos;t have access
			to a copy, you can go to <b>https://github.com/debrief/NaturalEarth</b> and download it by
			clicking on the Download zip button (file size is approximately 25 MB).<br/>Once you have
			downloaded the zip-file, just unzip it in the normal way and save it to a safe place on
			your hard drive.</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Configuring Debrief with Natural Earth data">
		<description>The next step is to configure Debrief with the “<b>Natural Earth</b>” data:
				<br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Preferences</b> (or press <b>Alt</b>,<b>W</b>,<b>P</b>).<br/><b>2.</b>
			Click on <b>Maritime Analysis</b> and select <b>Natural Earth</b>.<br/><b>3.</b> Click on the <b>Browse</b>
			to navigate to your unzipped <b>Natural Earth</b> folder.<br/><b>4.</b> Click on
			<b>Ok</b>.</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>