<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Configuring legacy data">
	<intro>
		<description>
			In addition to plotting your recorded vehicle data, Debrief is able
			to show a number of datasets in backdrop form.
			<br />
			These range from Vectored datasets such as VPF through to gridded
			datasets such as ETOPO-2
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item		
		title="Locating the coastline file">
		<description>
			In your Debrief installation directory is a file named <b>world.dat</b>.
			This is a fairly coarse global coastline.  For Debrief to plot coastlines
			we need to tell Debrief where the file is.
			<br/>
			So, go into <b>Window/Preferences</b>, then open up <b>Maritime Analysis</b>,
			then <b>Coastline file location</b>. Lastly, click on <b>Browse</b>
			to navigate to the <b>World.dat</b> file in your Debrief installation 
			folder.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#getting_vpf"
		title="How to configure VPF library datasets" skip="true">
		<description>
			The steps to configure VPF and Etopo are covered in Debrief&apos;s
			user manual. <i>NoPrint</i>If you wish to learn this at this stage, use the
			&apos;Question Mark&apos; help link alongside, else search for
			VPF
			in Debrief&apos;s online help at some future stage.<i>NoPrint</i>
			Here&apos;s a
			clue though, you go into the
			<b>Maritime Analysis</b>
			section of the Preferences. <br/> VPF is distributed as 4 CD-ROMS. If 
			you don&apos;t hold the CDs you can skip this step.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/etopo_data.html#etopo_install"
		title="How to configure ETOPO library data" skip="true">
		<description>
			<i>NoPrint</i>
			Use the help link to the side of this text to open the guidance on
			how to configure the location of the ETOPO data.
			<i>NoPrint</i>
			<i>Please read the relevant section of the Debrief user manual for how
				to specify use the Debrief/Preferences dialog the location of the ETOPO dataset.
				</i> 
				<br/>ETOPO is distributed as a ~200Mb data-file.  If 
			you don&apos;t hold the data-file you can skip this step.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
