<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Creating a new plot in Debrief">
   <intro>
      <description>This tutorial will guide you through creating a new, blank &apos;plot&apos; in
         Debrief.</description>
   </intro>
   <item title="Check you have a Project">
      <description><b>Plots</b> are stored in <b>projects</b>, so before you create a <b>plot</b>, you must have a
         <b>project</b>. If you don&apos;t have one, refer to <b>Generating a project for your data</b> and follow
         the steps there.</description>
   </item>
   <item title="Create new plot">
      <description>To create a new <b>plot</b>, in the <b>Navigator</b> view:<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click on the
         parent folder for your new plot and select <b>New/Debrief Plot</b>; the Wizard will open.
           <br/><b>2.</b> Next, either confirm where you would like the plot to be stored—this is
         called the <b>plot&apos;s container</b>—or select a different location by clicking on the <b>Browse</b>
         button and select the parent folder of your data directories.<br/><b>3.</b> Change the
         filename (as required).<br/><b>4.</b> Click on <b>Next</b>.<br/><b>5.</b> Now, select/deselect
         whether to use the <b>Natural Earth</b> dataset; click on <b>Next</b>.<br/><b>6.</b> Now you can choose
         whether to <b>Add Scale to Plot</b>, or not; including the following options: <b>color</b>, <b>display
            units</b>, and <b>scale location</b>.<br/>If you select to include a scale, you must enter the display
         units and scale location to proceed to the next step.<br/><b>7.</b> Next you can choose
         whether to <b>include a coastline</b> or not. This option is not mandatory.<br/><b>8.</b>
         Clicking on <b>Next</b> shows you last step in this process, the <b>Add Grid to Plot</b> dialog box.
           <br/><b>9.</b> Here you can select whether to <b>include</b> a grid, the grid <b>color</b>, whether to
         show <b>Plot Labels</b>, and the <b>Delta—grid step size</b>.<br/><b>10.</b> Once you have selected your
         options, click on the <b>Finish</b> button. The changes will be applied, and the dialog will
         close.</description>
   </item>
   <item title="Finished">
      <description>Your new plot (with the filename you used earlier), will then be displayed in
         your Debrief window. It is also located in the folder you specified in step 2 (above).
            <br/><b>Note:</b> all wizards make things easier for us, but all the steps above can be
         performed from the <b>Chart Features</b> menu in Debrief (<b>Alt</b>,<b>C</b>).</description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>