<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Main menu">
	<intro>
		<description>Without a Debrief file open, you will only see a reduced main menu set of 5
			items: <b>File</b>, <b>Edit</b>, <b>Run</b>, <b>Window</b>, and <b>Help</b>. So, we&apos;ll open a file to see the full set.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Opening a Debrief file">
		<description>To manage or open files, we need to go to the <b>Navigator</b> view. If it isn&apos;t
			open, open it. You can either:
			<br/><b>•</b> Click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Navigator</b>.
			<br/><b>•</b> Press <b>Ctrl + 3</b>
			> <b>Quick Access</b> > [click on <b>Navigator</b> - <b>General</b>].
			Now, in the <b>Navigator</b> view:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the drop-down arrow next to “<b>Debrief_test_project_01</b>” and it will expand.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the
			“<b>sample_data</b>” folder and locate the file “<b>boat1.rep</b>”.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Double-click on “<b>boat1.rep</b>” and
			the <b>Select track mode</b> dialog will show (remember, we accepted the default in <b>Preferences</b>
			to always ask us the track mode).
			<br/><b>4.</b> Select <b>Over the Ground (OTG)</b>.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Click on <b>Ok</b>. After a
			second or two, the <b>boat1.rep</b> plot will display in the <b>plot editor</b> part of the UI.
			<br/>You will also see the full main menu set as well as the main toolbar set.</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="The Main Menus">
		<description>The 8 main menus items are <b>File</b>, <b>Edit</b>, <b>Run</b>, <b>Chart</b> <b>Feature</b>, <b>Drawing</b>, <b>View</b>,
			<b>Window</b>, and <b>Help</b>. These are self-explanatory and mostly mirror many of the principal
			functions common throughout apps/programs today.
			<br/>Because of this, I won&apos;t run through
			what each do as the user guide contains that information, but will just add that you can
			only perform certain functions in Debrief if certain previous conditions have been met.
			If these conditions haven&apos;t been met, you won&apos;t be able to do them, e.g., the <b>Edit</b> >
			<b>Paste</b> function will be greyed-out and won&apos;t be available if you haven&apos;t yet copied
			anything to the clipboard. Similarly, you can&apos;t copy anything if nothing has actually
			been selected in the interface—I appreciate that you probably already knew this, but it
			does bear repeating.
			<br/>Using the menus is very easy, especially with the mouse. However,
			you can also access the main menu items using the keyboard. We&apos;ll discuss more about
			this in <b>Shortcut Key Combinations</b> (section 5).
			<br/>The second type of menu we have are
			called context-sensitive menus.</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Context-sensitive menus">
		<description>One mostly unused function when using the mouse with Windows is the
			right-click mouse button or the right-click keyboard button (this is the one with the
			graphic on it, normally 2 to the right of your keyboard&apos;s space-bar).
			<br/>Using either of
			these functions will cause a pop-up menu to appear—this is called a <b>context-sensitive
			menu</b>. Try it now.
			<br/>In the <b>plot editor</b>:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click on the grey area of the plot. You
			will see a popup menu with 3 options: <b>Copy Cursor Location</b>, <b>Edit base chart</b>, and <b>Edit
			Projection</b>.
			<br/>Admittedly, these aren&apos;t much help to us at the moment, but it&apos;s a quick way
			of accessing required information or attributes and functions of the chosen object (in
			this case, it was the grey background area—the sea).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Now, at the top of the track (the
			entire line on the plot is the track), you can see a straight yellow section.
			Right-click anywhere on it and a context-sensitive menu with a large range of options
			will display.
			<br/><b>3.</b> The 3rd option down is <b>Reset color</b>; select it and that small part of the
			yellow track will change color to red.
			<br/>Of course, there are many other things we can do
			with these options, but it&apos;s handy to know they are there and it&apos;s far quicker than
			using the main menu all the time.
			<br/>You might think this is no big deal but, when you&apos;re
			using a computer all day, shortcuts like this help enormously. As well as saving you
			time and energy, these context-sensitive menus also show you what other functionality is
			available to you and, as well as being a neat training aid, are great for improving your
			efficiency and capability with the program. The last menu set is the view drop-down
			menu.
			  </description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="View Drop-down Menus">
		<description>All views have a drop-down menu which further narrows-in on the functionality
			for the particular subset of tasks you are performing. For example, not only can you
			right-click on every individual element or attribute in a view, but you can also click
			on objects such as column headings, as well as the small drop-down arrow in the top
			right-hand corner of each view: each one will provide with you a new set of options
			specific to that attribute/view.
			<br/>With our <b>boat1.rep</b> file:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Identify the <b>Outline</b> view
			(if it isn&apos;t visible, open it: <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Outline</b>).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Within that view,
			click on <b>Track:NELSON</b> to expand it. You should see <b>120500.00 (402 items)</b> as the first
			item in the list (this contains the information about the entire track in our plot
			editor).
			<br/><b>3.</b> Right-click on <b>120500.00 (402 items)</b>.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Mouse-over <b>120500.00</b> and another
			popup will show.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Mouse-over <b>Linestyle</b> and select <b>Long dashes</b>. The track now changes to
			long dashes.
			<br/>Next, we&apos;ll go one step up:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Still in the <b>Outline</b> view, right-click
			on <b>Track:NELSON</b>.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Mouse-over <b>NELSON</b> and a popup will show.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Mouse-over <b>Color</b> and
			select <b>Blue</b>, most of the track will change color to blue.
			<br/>Now, we&apos;ll go another
			step up, this time to the view-level:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Outline</b> view&apos;s drop down arrow
			(in the top right corner).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Hide Item</b> and the track will disappear from the plot
			(it&apos;s still there, just hidden).
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click on the drop-down arrow again and select
			<b>Reveal Item</b>, it will show again in the plot editor.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> you can perform these
			functions at different levels in the view, e.g., you can also hide/reveal at the track
			and node levels, but it all depends on what you are actually working on in the plot
			editor.</description>
	</item>
	
</cheatsheet>