<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Debrief Preferences">
	<intro>
		<description>As mentioned, all software is configured a certain way &apos;out of the
			box&apos;, and Debrief is no different. However, it&apos;s most likely that you&apos;ll
			either want to change the way it&apos;s setup or know where to make the changes if you
			later decide to do so. For example, if you prefer <b>Over the Ground (OTG)</b> as the
			default import mode for track files, then you can change the setting here; the same if
			you wanted your <b>default range units</b> in miles or nautical miles, etc.<br/>Debrief
			has a large number of different settings and configurations, all of which can be changed
			if you prefer alternatives to the preset ones. To change these:<br/><b>1.</b> In
			Debrief, click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Preferences</b>. The <b>Preferences</b> dialog will
			open.<br/>We will now look at some of the important settings. Though we won&apos;t
			change any (as it&apos;s setup just right for the subsequent tutorials), it&apos;s handy
			to know where they are.<br/><b>2.</b> Click on <b>Maritime Analysis</b> and you will
			see 3 settings groups: <b>Default Track Import Mode</b>, <b>Default Range Units</b>, and
				<b>Relative Bearing Format</b>.<br/><b>3.</b> Again, we will leave these at the
			default setting, but just check that you want <b>Ask User</b> for the <b>Default track
				import mode</b>, <b>yd</b> for the <b>Default range units</b>; and <b>UK format
				(R180,,G180)</b> for the <b>Relative bearing format</b>. If not, make your
			change(s).<br/><b>4.</b> Once you are done, click on the <b>Apply</b> button to commit
			the changes: <b>Apply</b> makes the changes and leaves the dialog box open, whereas
			clicking on <b>Ok</b> commits the changes and closes the box.<br/>Now we will look at
			the different location format options<br/><b>6.</b> Click on the drop-down arrow next
			to <b>Maritime Analysis</b> and select <b>Formatting</b>.<br/><b>7.</b> You can now
			choose your location format, either <b>DD°MM.MMM&apos;</b> or <b>DD°MM&apos;
			SS.SSS”</b>—again, we want the default option.<br/><b>8.</b> If you have downloaded the
				“<b>Natural Earth</b>” set, click on this in the <b>Maritime Analysis</b> sub-menu.
				<br/><b>9.</b> Click on the <b>Browse</b> button, navigate to the download location,
			and double-click on the file to load it.<br/><b>10.</b> Finally, click on the <b>Ok</b>
			button.<br/>Those are the only settings we need for our tutorials. For the other
			preference settings, refer to the user guide for further information. Now we will look
			at working with Debrief.</description>
	</intro>
</cheatsheet>