<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Editing your data" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>So, you&apos;ve found your data, loaded it into Debrief, and now you want to make
			some changes to it. This cheat-sheet will give you some pointers.</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Check you have data" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cnav.htm">
		<description>
			To check that you have data:
			<br/>As before, open <b>Navigator</b> if it is closed (<b>Ctrl+3</b> then click on <b>Previous Choices</b> or type ‘navigator&apos; in the search field and click on it when it appears).
			<br/>Confirm you have sample data-files in navigator.
			<br/>If not, refer to the <b>Viewing Some Data</b> cheat-sheet.
			<b>Note:</b> valid Debrief files are flagged with a Debrief icon. Refer to the <b>Debrief File Formats</b> chapter in the <b>Debrief User Guide</b> to learn more about the two file types.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the sample plot file">
		<description>If necessary, double-click on <b>sample.dpf</b> in the <b>Navigator</b> view; the sample plot will open.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/moving_around.html" title="Fit to window">
		<description> You can also experiment with zooming in and out.
			<br/>Click the <b>Zoom Out</b> button once to zoom out, or you can put the plot into <b>Zoom In Mode</b> by
			clicking on the <b>Zoom In</b> button. Now, when you drag an area, the map will zoom in
			on that viewport.
			<br/>Lastly, to make sure all of the data is visible, click on the
			<b>Fit-to-Window</b> toolbar button. <i>NoPrint</i>Read more about the toolbar buttons by clicking on the help-link to
			the right of this text.<i>NoPrint</i> You can also find further information in the <b>Moving
				around the view</b> section of the <b>Debrief User Guide</b>.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> if you hover your mouse cursor over any button, 
			a tooltip explaining its function will appear.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="View the data in tree form">
		<description> In addition to viewing your data on the 2D plot, the <b>Outline View</b>
			displays it in tree form. Switch to the <b>Outline View</b> view to see the data. 
			If the Outline View isn&apos;t open already, you can open it via the <b>Window/Show View</b> menu.
			You&apos;ll see the two tracks there, together with other layers that contain <b>Chart
				Features</b> (such as the <b>Grid</b> and <b>Scale</b>), and the <b>Misc</b> layer
			that contains graphical annotations. </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Ensure the properties view is open"
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cpropview.htm">
		<description>The <b>Properties</b> view is normally at the bottom left of Debrief. If it&apos;s there
			but hidden behind other views, click on its title to reveal it. If you can&apos;t find
			it, select <b>Properties</b> from the <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> drop-down list (<b>Alt</b>, <b>W</b>, <b>V</b>, <b>P</b>).
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Select an item">
		<description>Now double-click on one of the corners of the green rectangle near the centre
			of the track plot. You&apos;ll now see its editable attributes appear on the properties
			window. Great. You&apos;ll see that the attributes are grouped for ease of use, and some
			must be expanded (those for location and time).</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Make a change">
		<description>
			To change the rectangle&apos;s label colour:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click once on the green rectangle next to <b>LabelColor</b>; a button with an ellipsis will appear.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the ellipsis to open the <b>color editor</b>.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Next, click on the red rectangle, and then the <b>OK</b> button.
			<br/>The dialog will close, the label color property will be updated, and the plot will redraw.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Undo the change">
		<description>
			Our new colour actually doesn&apos;t meet the NATO MilStd 12332 Sub-para 14g (2002 version) standard, so we need to undo it:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the tab at the top of the <b>sample.dpf</b> plot window (this makes the desired plot &apos;active&apos;).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the <b>Edit</b> menu
			<br/><b>3.</b> Select <b>Undo</b>.
			<br/>The color of the label will now change back: you&apos;ve undone a step.
			<br/>Now that you&apos;ve undone an action, if you click on the <b>Edit</b> menu again, you&apos;ll see a <b>Redo</b> option available - in case you couldn&apos;t care less about adhering to sub-para 14g.
			<br/>The <b>undo/redo</b> feature is a common to most programs and can be applied to lots of functions. The shortcut keys for these are <b>Ctrl+Z</b> and <b>Ctrl+Y</b> respectively (I use the former a lot).
			<br/>Bear in mind that the <b>Undo</b> button applies to the active Debrief view, so you must first select the plot to make it &apos;active&apos; before pressing undo.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Edit a position">
		<description> To select a position within a track, double-click on it and its
			editable attributes will appear in the properties view.
			<br/>You can change the symbol or label visibility (<b>SymbolShowing</b> or <b>LabelShowing</b>), and the <b>Color</b> that position is plotted in.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> different elements have different properties, so you
			may have to scroll up and down the Properties Window to see all the available properties.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Edit a whole track">
		<description>
			To edit an entire track, we use the <b>Outline View</b>, which makes selecting a plot easy.
			<br/>To open the <b>Outline View</b>:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Outline View</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> In the <b>Outline View</b>, click once on the name of a track and all the track&apos;s properties will be editable in the <b>Properties View</b>.
			<br/>The <b>Outline View</b> is also useful for selecting and editing non-geographical entities, such as a grid, scale and background data-set.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Rearranging your views">
		<description>Rearranging views in Debrief is a simple case of dragging views upwards. So, click on the <b>Properties</b> panel and drag it upwards.
			<br/>You will now be able to see the <b>Outline View</b> and <b>Properties</b> views at the same time.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Edit directly from the plot itself">
		<description> It is possible to edit certain attributes by right-clicking on an item on the
			plot. A popup menu will appear showing a series of available options and commands. A
			drop-down menu is shown next to the current item&apos;s name, from which you can edit the respective attributes.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> if you click on a vehicle	position, a drop-down appears for the parent track as well as the position itself.
			<br/>Right-click functionality is available from anywhere in the program to offer options related to the tasks or actions at hand.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Remember to save">
		<description>
			Anyone who has used computers for any length of time will have lost work at some point, so be sure to save your work regularly. You can save your work quickly by clicking on the floppy-disk icon on the main toolbar, or by pressing <b>Ctrl+S</b>.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> if the data you&apos;re using is in the rep file format, formatting data will not be stored; therefore, you will be prompted to save the file in Debrief&apos;s dpf plot-file format.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>