<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Editing your data" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>Now we&apos;ve got a complex plot open, we&apos;ll experiment with
			making some changes to it.</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Check you have data" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cnav.htm">
		<description>To check that you have data:<br/><b>1.</b> As before, open <b>Navigator</b> if it is
			closed (<b>Ctrl</b>+<b>3</b> then clicking on <b>Previous Choices</b>, or typing in &apos;navigator&apos;
			into the search field and clicking on it when it appears).<br/><b>2.</b> Confirm you
			have sample data-files in the <b>Navigator</b> view. If not, refer to the <b>Viewing Some Data</b>
			cheat-sheet.<br/><b>Note:</b> valid Debrief files are flagged with a Debrief icon.
			Refer to the <b>Debrief File Formats</b> chapter in the <b>Debrief User Guide</b> to learn more about
			the two file types.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the sample plot file">
		<description>If necessary, double-click on <b>sample.dpf</b> in the <b>Navigator</b> view; the sample plot will open.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/moving_around.html" title="Fit to window">
		<description>You can also experiment with zooming in and out. Click the <b>Zoom Out</b> button once
			to zoom out, or you can put the plot into <b>Zoom In Mode</b> by clicking on the <b>Zoom In</b>
			button. Now, when you drag an area, the map will zoom in on that viewport. Lastly, to
			make sure all of the data is visible, click on the <b>Fit-to-Window</b> toolbar button.<i>NoPrint</i> Read more about the toolbar buttons
			by clicking on the help-link to the right of this text.<i>NoPrint</i><br/>You can
			read more about the toolbar buttons in the <b>Moving around the view section</b> of the Debrief
			User Guide.<br/><b>Note:</b> if you hover your mouse cursor over any button, a tooltip
			explaining its function will display.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Ensure the properties view is open"
		href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cpropview.htm">
		<description>The <b>Properties</b> view is normally at the bottom left of Debrief. If it&apos;s
			there but not at the top of the &apos;stack&apos;, click on its tab to reveal it. If you
			can&apos;t find it, select <b>Properties</b> from the <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> drop-down list
			(<b>Alt</b>,<b>W</b>,<b>V</b>,<b>P</b>).</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Select an item">
		<description>You can select an item on the on the plot by double-clicking on it.
				<br/><b>1.</b> Identify the chart feature named <b>Some Label</b>. To the right of it is a
			red circle.<br/><b>2.</b> Double-click on the circle to select it. In the <b>Outline</b> view,
			you will see that the object <b>Label:Some Label</b> has been selected and, in the <b>Properties</b>
			view, you can see that the properties for the object you selected are listed, including:
			<b>Color</b>, <b>Font</b>, <b>Location</b>, etc.<br/><b>3.</b> Now, double-click anywhere on the <b>NOGO DELTA</b>
			rectangle to select that feature.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Make a change">
		<description>To change the rectangle&apos;s label color:<br/><b>1.</b> Click once on the
			green rectangle next to <b>Label color</b>. A button containing an ellipsis will appear.
				<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the ellipsis to open the <b>color editor</b>.<br/><b>3.</b> Next,
			click on the red rectangle, and then the <b>OK</b> button.<br/>The dialog will close, the label
			color property will be updated, and the plot will redraw.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Undo the change">
		<description>Our new color doesn&apos;t meet the NATO MilStd 12332 Sub-para 14g (2002
			version) standard, so we need to undo it:<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the tab at the top of
			the <b>sample.dpf</b> plot (to select the correct plot—when something is selected, we call this
			active).<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the <b>Edit</b> menu<br/><b>3.</b> Select <b>Undo</b>. The color of
			the label will now change back—you&apos;ve undone 1 step.<br/>Now that you&apos;ve undone an
			action, if you click on the <b>Edit</b> menu again, you&apos;ll see there&apos;s now a <b>Redo</b>
			option available. This undo/redo feature is common to most programs and can be applied
			to many functions. The shortcut keys for these are <b>Ctrl+Z</b> and <b>Ctrl+Y</b> respectively (I use
			the former a lot).<br/>One point to note is the <b>Undo</b> button applies to the active Debrief
			view; so, to undo a change to a plot, you must first select the plot and make it active
			before pressing undo.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Edit a position">
		<description>To select a position within a track, double-click on that position and its
			editable attributes will appear in the <b>Properties</b> view. You can modify all of these
			attributes (as required).<br/><b>Note:</b> different elements have different
			properties, so you may have to scroll up and down the <b>Properties</b> view to see all
			available properties.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Edit an entire track">
		<description>To edit an entire track, we use the <b>Outline</b> view. This makes selecting a plot
			easy. To open the <b>Outline</b> view:<br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Outline
			View</b>.<br/><b>2.</b> In the <b>Outline</b> view, click once on the name of a track and the
			entire track&apos;s properties will be editable in the <b>Properties</b> view.<br/>The <b>Outline</b> view
			is also useful for selecting and editing non-geographic entities such as a grid, scale,
			or background data-set.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Rearranging your views">
		<description>Rearranging views within Debrief is a simple case of dragging views to where
			you wish to locate them. So, click on the <b>Properties</b> panel tab and drag it upwards. You
			will now be able to see the <b>Outline</b> and <b>Properties</b> views at the same time.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Edit directly from the plot itself">
		<description>It&apos;s possible to edit certain attributes by right-clicking on an item on
			the plot. A popup menu will display showing a series of available options and commands.
			A drop-down menu is shown next to the current item&apos;s name and, from this drop-down
			menu, you&apos;ll be able to edit the respective attributes.<br/><b>Note:</b> if you
			click on a vehicle position, a drop-down is shown for the parent track as well as the
			position itself. Also note that right-click functionality is available from anywhere
			within the program and relevant options will be shown related to the tasks or actions
			you are currently undertaking.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Remember to save">
		<description>Anyone who has used computers for any length of time will have lost work at
			some point, so ensure you save your work regularly. You can save your work quickly by
			clicking on the floppy-disk icon on the main toolbar or by pressing <b>Ctrl</b>+<b>S</b>.
				<br/><b>Note:</b> if the data you&apos;re using is actually a rep file, these cannot
			store formatting data, so you will be prompted to save the file in Debrief&apos;s DPF
			plot-file format.</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>