<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Generating links to existing data stored on your machine"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>Debrief NG stores it&apos;s data in a local folder called a Project. While
			these are frequently created afresh to store new analysis data, it&apos;s also possible
			to denote your existing data directories as sub-folders (via links). This tutorial leads
			you through generating links to your existing data folders. But, if the "Create Project" 
			form opened at application startup, you
			provided a project name, and indicated that you would like sample data to be imported,
			then you can skip the following steps and move on to the next cheat sheet.
			<br/>
			You should also skip this set of tasks if you can see a <b>Sample Data</b> folder in your Navigator,
			since you must have already created the necessary link(s).
			<br/>
			Lastly, you should skip this set of tasks if you run Debrief from a network share.  The 
			next set of tasks (for <b>shared folder</b>) are the correct set for your situation. </description>
	</intro>
	<item
       skip="true"
       title="Check Navigator is open">
		<description>In the top left hand corner of Debrief you should find the Navigator window. If
			it isn&apos;t there, select <b>Navigator</b> from Debrief&apos;s Window/Show View
			menu.</description>
	</item>
	<item
       skip="true"
       title="Check you have a workspace">
		<description>Before you can link in existing data, you need to define a project for your
			work. This is a parent folder within which your links are stored. If your Navigator
			window is empty, you must follow the <b>Generating a project</b> cheat-sheet <i>NoPrint</i>accessed
			from the Help/Cheat Sheets menu<i>NoPrint</i><i>Earlier in this document</i>.</description>
	</item>
	<item
       skip="true"
       title="Add a new Folder">
		<description>Right-click on your current project in the Navigator view, then select
				<b>Folder</b> from the <b>New</b> sub-menu. The New Folder wizard will open. Instead
			of creating a fresh child folder to store our data, we&apos;re going to link to an
			existing folder. So, whilst still in the New Folder Wizard, click the
			&apos;Advanced&apos; button to display the Advanced options. Next, click on the
			&apos;Link to alternate location (Linked folder)&apos;, and click on
			&apos;Browse...&apos; to navigate to an existing data folder on your machine or the
			network, clicking on <b>Finish</b> to, erm, Finish. <br/><b>If you don&apos;t have your own
			data</b>, please use the <b>sample_data</b> folder that&apos;s installed in your Debrief
			installation folder (for a deployed Debrief) or<br/>
			org.mwc.cmap.combined.feature/root_installs (if you are running a development version of
			Debrief).</description>
	</item>
	<item
       skip="true"
       title="Done">
		<description>Well done, there you are. Just repeat this process to add any other data
			directories you want to load data from. You&apos;ve probably just created a link to the
			sample data, but you may also wish to create a link to a shared working
			folder.</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
