<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Generating links to existing data stored on your machine"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>As mentioned previously, Debrief NG stores its data in a local &apos;Project&apos;
			folder. While these are frequently created from scratch to store new analysis data, you
			can also set your existing data directories as sub-folders (via links).<br/>The
			following procedure guides you through generating links to your existing data folders.
			However, if the <b>Create Project</b> form opened when the application started and you
			provided both a project name and indicated that you would like sample data to be
			imported, then you can skip the following steps and move on to the next cheat sheet,
				<b>Viewing some data</b>.</description>
	</intro>
	<item skip="true" title="Open Navigator if it is closed">
		<description>Open <b>Navigator</b> if it is closed by using the <b>Ctrl+3</b> shortcut and
			then either clicking on the option in <b>Previous Choices</b> or typing
			&apos;navigator&apos; in the search field and clicking on it when it appears.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item skip="true" title="Check you have a workspace">
		<description>Before you can link existing data, you need to define a project for your work:
			a &apos;project&apos; is a parent folder which stores your links. If your <b>Navigator</b> view is empty,
			you must first complete the <b>Generating a project for your data</b> cheat-sheet (above).
		</description>
	</item>
	<item skip="true" title="Add a new Folder">
		<description>
			To add a new folder:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click on your current project in the <b>Navigator</b> view, the <b>New</b> sub-menu will show.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Folder</b> and the <b>New Folder</b> wizard will open.
			<br/>Here though, instead of creating a fresh child folder to store our data, we&apos;re going to link to an existing folder.
			<br/><b>3.</b> In the <b>New Folder</b> wizard, click on the <b>Advanced</b> button and the <b>Advanced</b> options will show.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Select <b>Link to alternate location (Linked folder)</b>.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Click on the <b>Browse...</b> button and navigate to an existing data folder on your machine or network location.
			<br/><b>6.</b> Once complete, click on <b>Finish</b> to close the wizard and link to your existing data.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> if you don&apos;t have your own data, use either of the following:
			<br/><b>•</b> For a deployed Debrief, use the <b>sample_data</b> folder installed in your Debrief installation folder.
			<br/><b>•</b> If you are running a development version of Debrief, use <b>org.mwc.cmap.combined.feature/root_installs</b>.
			<br/>If you followed these steps, you will have created a link to the sample data, however, if you need to load data from other data directories, repeat this process as often as is required, but use a shared working folder.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
