<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Generating a project for your data"
   xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
   xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
   <intro>
      <description>Debrief NG stores data in a local folder called <b>Project</b>. You place analysis files and links to existing data folders on your machine/network into this folder. This tutorial will lead you through creating a new, blank project.
      </description>
   </intro>
   <item title="Check Navigator is open">
      <description>In the top left hand corner of Debrief you should find the Navigator window. If it is open, close it; if it isn&apos;t there these next steps will show you how to open it:        
         <br/><b>1.</b> click on <b>Window</b> on the menu bar         
         <br/><b>2.</b> mouseover or click on <b>Show View</b>
         <br/><b>3.</b> click on <b>Navigator</b>
         <br/>The <b>Navigator</b> window will then display. A much faster (old school) alternative is to use key stroke sequences on your keyboard to perform specific actions.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item skip="true" title="Shortcut key combinations">
      <description>
         If you&apos;re an old school type who, like me, prefers to use the keyboard where possible, then you can use what are called keyboard combinations. 
         Keyboard combinations consist of a sequence of keys which perform a certain action in the program. 
         For example, a common keyboard combination/shortcut in any program is <b>Ctrl+S</b> to quickly save your current document. 
         Similarly, the <b>Navigator</b> can be quickly opened via a keyboard combination:
         <br/><b>1.</b> Press <b>Ctrl+3</b> on your keyboard, and the <b>Quick Access</b> popup dialog will show.
         <br/><b>2.</b> Start typing ‘navigator’ in the dialog box and, before you’ve finished typing the word, you will see <b>Views - Navigator - General</b>; 
         click on it and the <b>Navigator</b> dialog will appear in the top left of your window.
            <br/>The next time you need to do this, press <b>Ctrl+3</b> and you’ll see <b>Previous Choices</b> right under the field where you type - just click on it.
      </description>
   </item>
   
   <item skip="true" title="Other key combinations">
      <description>
         Throughout these cheat sheets, you will see other combinations like:
         <br/><b>•Alt+[key]</b> means <b>press and hold</b> the <b>Alt</b> key and, while it is still pressed, press the other key (or keys).
         <br/><b>•Alt, [key]</b> means you press and release the <b>Alt</b> key and then press the next key(s).
         <br/><b>Note:</b>  sometimes, both variations will work (mainly for common Windows-type tasks), but all programs have their differences.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item skip="true" title="How to find out what the shortcut keys are">
   <description>
      To find out what other shortcut keys work:
      <br/><b>1.</b> Press the <b>Alt</b> key and observe how the letters of each meno item is underlined.
      <br/><b>2.</b> By pressing any one of those underlined letters on your keyboard, the common commands in the corresponding menu will appear.
      <br/>In these drop-down sub-menus, you will see pre-programmed keyboard combinations next to the more popular commands, e.g., in the <b>File</b> menu (<b>Alt, F</b>  or <b>ALt+F</b>) you will see that the shortcut key to <b>Print</b> is <b>Ctrl+P</b> - this is the same in the vast majority of Windows applications. 
      Try and remember these, as they can speed up your work in Debrief.
   </description>
   </item>
   <item skip="true" title="Learn about the show view menu">
      <description>If the Navigator view was already open, you may have missed an important feature in Debrief, the <b>Show View</b> menu. Views are supplemental panels that provide additional information (or control) to the conventional 2D Debrief plot, and there are a number of views available.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item skip="true" title="Opening a view">
      <description>
         To open a view:
         <br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Window</b> menu item
         <br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Show view</b> and a list of Debrief-specific views open.
         <br/><b>3.</b> Click on the view you require to open in it the Debrief window.
         <br/>So, in the future, when you&apos;re directed to a view and you can&apos;t find it on your screen, just remember you can open any view from this menu.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item skip="true" title="Closing a view">
      <description>
         Views can be closed by clicking on the X icon on their name tab.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item skip="true" title="Moving a view">
      <description>
         Views can also be dragged around, both within Debrief to reposition them, or to a separate external window. When you close Debrief, it remembers the views that were previously open.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="Learn about the Quick Access panel">
      <description>
         Alternatively, wherever you are in Debrief, you can open the quick access panel. Just <b>press and hold</b> the <b>Ctrl key</b>, and then press <b>3</b> and a yellow post-it like menu will appear. As you start typing &apos;Navigator&apos; the list of available commands will reduce until your required view is open. 
         If you prefer to use the mouse, click on <b>Window > Navigation > Quick Access</b>.
         <br/>When you see &apos;<b>menu > sub-menu item > item</b>&apos; in this document, it means click on the first item, then on the second, and so on. I’m sure you’ve seen this before; it’s a much tidier than writing:
         <br/><b>1.</b> Click on <b>Window</b>
         <br/><b>2.</b> Then click on <b>Navigation</b>
         <br/><b>3.</b> and so on...
         <br/>I think you’ll agree that the second method is far more cumbersome. We will still use the second approach for step-by-step procedures, however.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="Check you need a project">
      <description>If you have to create a project please move on to the next step. If the <b>Navigator</b> window is empty, then you will need to create a new project. If the window already contains a folder-icon (possibly containing sample data) then you&apos;re ready to go, and can move on to the next cheat sheet.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item title="Create a &apos;general&apos; project" dialog="true">
      <description>
         To create a &apos;general&apos; project:
         <br/><b>1.</b> Right-click anywhere in the <b>Navigator</b> view, the <b>New</b> sub-menu will display
         <br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Project...</b>
         <br/><b>3.</b> The <b>New Project wizard</b> will open
         <br/><b>4.</b> Click on <b>General</b> > <b>Project</b>
         <br/><b>5.</b> Click on the <b>Next</b> button; you will now <b>Create a new project resource</b>
         <br/><b>6.</b> Enter a name for your project (perhaps the name of the current exercise, or another meaningful name).
         <br/>If you&apos;re in a workplace where users are unable to create folders in their home directory, clear the <b>Use default location</b> checkbox, and <b>Browse</b> to a folder in your personal working directories
         <br/><b>Note:</b> you can ignore &apos;Working Sets&apos; for now
         <br/><b>7.</b> Click on the <b>Finish</b> button
         <br/>You will see the new project in your workspace.
      </description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
