<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Adding data to a plot">
	<intro>
		<description>Debrief&apos;s <b>New Plot</b> wizard is effective at providing you with a
			preformatted backdrop to your analysis, but it doesn&apos;t load your data for you. We
			will now load some existing tracks to assist you in getting started.</description>
	</intro>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/import_range_data.html#DebrieffileFormat"
		title="Check sample data">
		<description>To check sample data:<br/><b>1.</b> Open <b>Navigator</b> (using your mouse, or
			<b>Ctrl</b>+<b>3</b> and typing the search term).<br/><b>2.</b> Expand the folder that contains your
			existing Debrief files (these will be either REP or DPF).<br/><b>Note:</b> valid
			Debrief files are flagged with a Debrief icon. Refer to the <b>Debrief File Formats</b> chapter
			in the <b>Debrief User Guide</b> to learn more about the two file types.</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/import_range_data.html#import_modes"
		title="Drag in a simple track">
		<description>If you&apos;ve already got a plot open, close it now by clicking on the cross
			in the small tab-shaped icon above it. Don&apos;t worry about saving the tutorial files.
			Drag a <b>rep</b> track from your <b>Navigator</b> onto the blank plot area. The <b>boat1.re</b>p file is a
			simple starting point. The plot and any associated views will promptly update. When <b>rep</b>
			files are dragged in, you may be asked whether you wish to import the data in <b>Over The
			Ground (OTG)</b> or <b>Dead Reckoning (DR)</b> mode. For this tutorial, select <b>OTG</b>.<br/><i>NoPrint</i> Use the help link (?) to the side of this text to open the
			guidance on using OTG and DR data. <i>NoPrint</i>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Drag in a complex plot">
		<description>If you have multiple tracks to analyse, you can drag them onto the track
			plot you&apos;ve just created. But for now, close the plot you have open by clicking on
			the cross icon in its tab and press <b>Don&apos;t Save</b> when asked.<br/>Now, drag <b>sample.dpf</b>
			into the plot area. You&apos;ll see that this plot contains more complex graphical
			features.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Debrief file types">
		<description>Note, you&apos;ve just encountered two file types, the <b>Replay</b> file type (.rep )
			and the <b>Debrief</b> file type (.dpf).<br/>The two file types differ in that though the rep file
			format is a very simple, column oriented text format ideal for passing around track data
			and for getting your raw track data into Debrief (see the Reference section in the user
			manual for more details), it isn&apos;t suited to storing formatting data or user
			preferences; in contrast, with its textual XML structure and ability to store a wide
			range of data, the dpf file format is.<br/>As such, a typical flow is that data enters
			Debrief in rep format and an analyst uses this data to create a custom plot; this plot
			is then stored in XML format as a DPF file.<br/>Your track data is now on the plot.
				<br/><b>Note:</b> tracks can be dragged into Debrief from other areas, such as
			“<b>Windows Explorer</b>”. <i>NoPrint</i>Refer to the <b>Maintainer&apos;s Guide</b> section of the <b>Debrief User
				Guide</b> to learn how to support right-click track opening on MS Windows.<i>NoPrint</i></description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>