<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Adding data to a plot">
	<intro>
		<description>Debrief&apos;s <b>New Plot</b> wizard is effective at providing you with a preformatted backdrop to your analysis, but it doesn&apos;t load your data for you.
			<br/>We will now load some existing tracks to assist you in getting started.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/import_range_data.html#DebrieffileFormat"
		title="Check sample data">
		<description>
			To check sample data:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Open <b>Navigator</b> (using your mouse, or <b>Ctrl+3</b> and typing the search term).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Expand the folder that contains your existing Debrief files (these will be either REP or DPF).
			<b>Note:</b> valid Debrief files are flagged with a Debrief icon. Refer to the <b>Debrief File Formats</b> chapter in the <b>Debrief User Guide</b> to learn more about the two file types.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/import_range_data.html#import_modes"
		title="Drag in a simple track">
		<description>If you&apos;ve already got a plot open, close it now by clicking on the cross in the
			small tab-shaped icon above it. Don&apos;t worry about saving the tutorial files.
			<br/>Drag a <b>rep</b> track from your <b>Navigator</b> onto the blank plot area. The <b>boat1.rep</b> file is a simple
			starting point. The plot and any associated views will promptly update.
			<br/>When rep files are dragged in, you may be asked whether you wish to import the data in &apos;Over The Ground&apos;
			(OTG) or &apos;Dead Reckoning&apos; (DR) mode. For this tutorial, select OTG.
			<i>NoPrint</i> Use the help link (?) to the side of this text to open the guidance on using OTG and DR data.
				<i>NoPrint</i>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Drag in a complex plot">
		<description> If you have multiple tracks to analyse, you can drag them onto the track plot
			you&apos;ve just created. But, for now, close the plot you have open by clicking on the cross
			icon in its tab and press <b>Don&apos;t Save</b>.
			<br/>Now, drag <b>sample.dpf</b> into the plot area. You&apos;ll see that this plot
			contains more complex graphical features.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Debrief file types">
		<description>
			Note, you&apos;ve just encountered two file types, the &apos;Replay&apos; file type (.rep) and the &apos;Debrief&apos; file type (.dpf).
			<br/>The 2 file types differ in that while the Replay file format is a very simple, column oriented text format ideal for passing around track data and getting your raw track data into Debrief (see the <b>Reference</b> section within the user manual for more details), rep files aren&apos;t suited to storing formatting data or user preferences; this is where the Debrief file type comes in: the textual XML file structure of the dpf files allows it to store a wide range of data.
			<br/>As such, a typical flow is that data enters Debrief in rep format and an analyst uses this data to create a custom plot, which is then stored in XML format as a dpf file.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/maintainers.html#RightClickIntegration"
		title="Done">
		<description> Your track data is now on the plot. <br/><b>Note:</b> tracks can be dragged
			into Debrief from other areas, such as Windows Explorer.<i>NoPrint</i> Refer to the
				<b>Maintainers Guide</b> section of the <b>Debrief User Guide</b> to learn how to
			support right-click track opening with MS Windows.<i>NoPrint</i>
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>