<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Main Toolbar">
	<intro>
		<description>The main, or <b>Workbench</b>, toolbar contains a combination of a number of mini
			toolbars (you can see a vertical dotted-line separating them), and grouped buttons (kept
			apart by a separator—vertical lines between the buttons). You can move the mini toolbars
			by clicking on the dotted lines and dragging horizontally or vertically; and, if you
			mouse-over any of the buttons, a button tooltip will appear explaining the main function
			of that button. The mini toolbars are as follows (from left to right):<br/><b>•</b> <b>Save</b> - this will
			save the project with the currently saved name.<br/><b>•</b> <b>Create project</b> - clicking here will
			initiate the <b>Create a project</b> wizard.<br/><b>•</b> <b>Drawing tools</b> - the drawing toolbar contains
			buttons which allow you to view plot layers or to place objects such as shapes, labels,
			range rings, tracks, and vectors onto the plot. Refer to the User Guide for further
			details.<br/><b>•</b> <b>Plot Management tools</b> - this group of 9 buttons is split into 3 parts by
			separators—solid vertical lines between buttons. These buttons allow you to perform
			various management functions within the plot editor, including object repositioning,
			measuring, zooming in and out, etc.<br/>From the left, the first group contains 6 buttons,
			and only one button of these can be selected at a time. The first 3 buttons of this
			group—<b>track segment</b>, <b>whole component</b> and <b>whole feature</b>—are used to drag and reposition
			objects on the plot. The next button is used to <b>measure range bearing</b> between 2 objects.
			To the right of that, and to the left of the first separator, are the <b>pan</b> and <b>zoom in</b>
			buttons which allow you reposition and increase plot magnification, respectively.<br/>To the
			right of the separator, in the second group, is the solitary <b>zoom out</b> button—its
			function is self-explanatory and this button can be used in conjunction with all the
			buttons in the first group.<br/>Finally, to the right of the second separator, in the third
			group, we have the <b>fit to window</b> and <b>redraw</b> plot editor buttons, respectively—again,
			these are self-explanatory.<br/><b>Note:</b> if you have also loaded the <b>Natural Earth</b> set, this
			will show in the toolbar area also.<br/>We won&apos;t go over all of these functions, so refer to
			the user guide when necessary.</description>
	</intro>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Show/Hide the main toolbar">
		<description> You can show/hide the main
			toolbar by clicking on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show/Hide Toolbar</b>.</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>