<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../contentFile.xsd"?>
<cheatsheet title="Welcome to DebriefNG (with Charts)">
	<intro>
		<description>The <b>Welcome</b> screen is displayed on your first visit to Debrief, but it
			is always accessible from within Debrief via the <b>Help</b> menu.<br/>When the page
			loads, you will see the following 5 buttons:<br/><b>• Overview</b> - if this is your
			first time using Debrief, it&apos;s a good idea to click on this button to get an
			overview of the features.<br/><b>• What&apos;s New</b> - we&apos;re constantly updating
			the software, so if you want to see the exciting new features, click on this
				button.<br/><b>• First Steps</b> - we all have to start somewhere; so, if you&apos;d
			rather read the first steps than follow this tutorial, then feel free to click
				here.<br/><b>• Tutorials</b> - if you click on this option, then you&apos;ll see
			another version of this tutorial. However, it&apos;s always handy to know where to find
				these.<br/><b>• Workbench</b> - the workbench is the main interface for performing
			your plot analysis and other tasks: this is the place where you will do all your work.
			<br/>We won&apos;t go into all the features or what you will find by clicking on the
			above, as I know you&apos;re raring to go. But, I would recommend you explore and
			familiarise yourself with those elements when you have the time.<br/>For the next
			sections, if you&apos;re an experienced computer user then you&apos;ll already know
			about <b>main menus</b>, <b>context-sensitive menus</b> and <b>toolbars</b>; if this is
			the case, feel free to skip them. However, I would recommend that you do read the
			section on <b>Views</b> as they are an important component of Debrief (starting at
			section 1.6)<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Goto Workbench</b> button. The
				<b>Welcome</b> screen will close and you will see the <b>Create Project</b> dialog
				box.<br/><b>2.</b> Every Debrief project requires a name, so you can go with the
			default name of <b>DebriefProject</b>, or enter something more meaningful. I will name
			mine “<b>Debrief_test_project_01</b>”.<br/><b>3.</b> You can leave the <b>Add Debrief
				Samples</b> and <b>Always Check at Startup</b> boxes checked.<br/><b>4.</b> Click on
			the <b>Ok</b> button. The dialog box will close and you will see an empty Debrief
			interface consisting of various items and objects (we will go over these in a
				second).<br/><b>5.</b> If you look in the <b>Navigator</b> &apos;window&apos;, you
			will see your new project name folder.<br/>In Debrief, this small window is called a
				<b>View</b>. There are different types of view, all of which perform different
			functions; e.g., if you click on the <b>Time Controller</b> tab (next to
				<b>Navigator</b>), you&apos;ll see we have a set of video-type controls: very useful
			for displaying time elements in Debrief.<br/>Underneath these 2 views are 3 other
			views: <b>Properties</b>, <b>Track Tote</b>, and <b>Chart Overview</b>; again, each of
			these views performs a different function. We won&apos;t look at these now, but these
			views and other interface items such as toolbars, menus, and the plot editor (the large
			empty space to the right of the views) make up a large part of Debrief.<br/>Though
			empty, the interface may seem a little daunting at first, but we&apos;ll work through
			all of these items and you&apos;ll come to realise that it&apos;s actually quite easy to
			work with.<br/>However, as with any new application, it&apos;s a good idea to configure
			it exactly how you want it for your own purposes. In Debrief, these are called
				<b>Preferences</b> and, though you don&apos;t know that much about the software as
			yet, you will understand each of these settings. </description>
	</intro>
</cheatsheet>