<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Working with views">
	<intro>
		<description>As mentioned, views are small viewing panes which present information specific
			to the task you are carrying out in the plot editor in different ways. For example, one
			view may display tabular information about the properties of an object: its position,
			its color, etc. (the <b>Properties</b> view); whereas, another will have video controls to show
			time (the <b>Time Controller</b> view); and yet another will show a graphical overview of the
			chart in use (the <b>Chart Overview</b> view). Again, views display supporting data or
			properties about the selected data or tasks. As you will see, they are an important
			element of Debrief and you will use them extensively. We&apos;ve already looked at opening
			and closing views, next we&apos;ll look at other view-related tasks.</description>
	</intro>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Active or Inactive?">
		<description>In any Windows program, we refer to items such as a window, a video, an image,
			some text, etc. as an &apos;object&apos;. An object can only have 2 states: it is either selected
			(<b>active</b>) or it isn&apos;t (<b>inactive</b>). The vast majority of the time, you can only
			work/perform an action on an active object, i.e., something that has been selected to
			work on.
			<br/>In addition, and this applies to most computer programs or applications, there
			has to be an active object: this is what you&apos;ve selected to work on or with. Naturally,
			if you want to work on an inactive object, then you must first make it active by
			selecting it (this applies in most cases, though not all). Debrief shows you which
			object is the active view with a blue <b>name tab</b> and blue border.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the <b>Outline</b>
			view in the bottom left of your window. It&apos;s name tab will turn blue, and you can see a
			blue border around the view. This is now the active object.
			<br/><b>2.</b> The Outlne view is still
			empty, so click on the <b>Navigator</b> view to select it (make it active), and you will now
			see some attributes in the <b>Properties</b> view.
			<br/><b>3.</b> In the <b>Properties</b> view, click on the <b>Info</b>
			attribute in the <b>Property</b> column: this attribute becomes the active property, and this
			view the active view.
			<br/><b>4.</b> In the same column, click on the <b>location</b> attribute; this is now
			the active attribute.
			<br/>To make an object inactive, click on a different object to select
			it; the new object is now active.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> there will be times when you will use the <b>Ctrl</b>
			and <b>Shift</b> key on your keyboard to select multiple objects; when this occurs, all
			selected items become active.
			<br/>Next, it&apos;s quite possible that you will want to reposition
			views as you work, so we will look at how to move them.</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Moving Views">
		<description>Moving views is very easy and they can be positioned anywhere around the plot
			editor by dragging-and-dropping. This is very handy as not only can you move the
			important features into prominent positions on your monitor when you need them, but you
			can also move them out of the way, onto another monitor (if you have multiple monitors),
			or even drop them into an already open view to stack them up (to save screen space). Try
			it:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the tab of any open view to make it active (remember, the tab will turn
			blue).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Now, click on the tab itself and, keeping the mouse button pressed, drag it
			across the plot editor area. As you approach the edges of the <b>plot editor</b>, you will see
			the cursor change to a black direction arrow and a placeholder box will appear to one
			side of the plot editor; if you wish, you can drop the view into place there.
			<br/><b>3.</b> However, if you drag it further, onto to another view, the cursor will change to a graphical set
			of files (or folders); you will also see a shaded border around the view you are over,
			showing you where it will be placed. If you drop it now, the view will add to that view
			set (or <b>stack</b>), and become active.
			<br/><b>4.</b> But, if you didn&apos;t drop it on the view, deciding
			instead to drop your cursor either onto the name tab of the view you are over or right
			next to it, you will see a dotted box appear showing you where your view will be placed.
			As soon as you drop the view, it will dock in that position and become the active view.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> within the confines of the central editor pane, you can also do the same with the
			plot editor.</description>
	</item>
	<item href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/external_datasets.html#ne_intro"
		title="Resizing Views">
		<description>In addition to the standard Windows <b>minimize</b> and <b>maximize</b> functionality (the
			two small icons in the top right-hand corner of each view), you can also resize views by
			moving your mouse cursor over the view&apos;s border. As soon as the cursor changes to a
			directional arrow, left-click on the border and then drag it in one of the indicated
			directions. Once it&apos;s in position, release the mouse button.
			</description>
	</item>
	
</cheatsheet>