<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Assigning primary and secondary tracks"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>In the next part of the tutorial, we will look at primary and secondary tracks,
			how we set them up, move tracks through time, etc. All this is done through a Debrief
			view called <b>Track Tote</b>. </description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Open Navigator" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cnav.htm">
		<description>If <b>Navigator</b> isn&apos;t visible, open it.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the sample plot-file">
		<description> Double-click on <b>sample.dpf</b> in the <b>Navigator</b> window, and the sample plot will
			open.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Fit to window"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\moving_around.html#Fit_To_Win">
		<description>To make sure all of the data is visible, click on the <b>Fit-to-Window</b> toolbar button.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="View the Track Tote"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\start_up.html#debrief_views">
		<description> In the centre section of the left hand column in Debrief is the <b>Track Tote</b>. If
			it isn&apos;t visible, open it by clicking on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Track Tote</b>.
			<br/>If it is open but hidden beneath other view panels, click on its tab to make it active.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="The Track Tote explained"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\analysing_data.html#the_tote_area">
		<description>The <b>Track Tote</b> contains information about selected tracks in the active
			plot. It displays at least one column for the active track plus the <b>Calculation</b>
			column, up to a maximum equalling the number of plots in the active area, plus the
			<b>Units</b> column, which you can hide.
			<br/>In our <b>sample.dpf</b> example, the left-hand track column contains the
			<b>primary track</b> data for &apos;Nelson&apos; and the right-hand
			column contains the <b>secondary track</b> data for &apos;Collingwood&apos;. All
			calculation data is taken from the corresponding track (the calculations themselves are
			explained in greater detail in the help manual).
			<br/><i>NoPrint</i> (click on the Help icon above)<i>NoPrint</i>.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Move track through time"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\analysing_data.html#stepping_forward_in_time">
		<description> Now we will use the time controller to change the time:
			<br/><b>1.</b> If the <b>Time Controller</b> is not visible, open it.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Drag the <b>time-slider</b> right and left, and you will
			see the calculated data fields update (you will also notice the white squares denoting the vessel positions move).
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Removing a track from the tote" href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\analysing_data.html#removing_tracks">
		<description> To remove a track from the tote:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click the &apos;Collingwood&apos; tote column (not the header) that is furthest to the right.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Remove this track</b>.
			<br/>The &apos;Collingwood&apos; <b>secondary tack</b> will be
			removed, leaving the remaining &apos;Nelson&apos; track.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Adding a track to the tote"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\analysing_data.html#assigning_tracks">
		<description> To add a track to the tote:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Open the <b>Outline View</b> - note the disabled buttons &apos;1&apos; and
			&apos;2&apos; on the view toolbar, they will become
			enabled when a currently selected item is suitable for inclusion on the tote.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click once on the track you just removed from the tote and both buttons will be enabled.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Make the track either primary or secondary, as you please.When you do so, it will appear in the tote again.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> Apart from tracks, any data item that has time and location attributes can be placed on the tote; circles and labels are particularly suitable.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
		<description>You have completed the tutorial on the <b>Track Tote</b> and now you know about
			primary, secondary and other tracks. As with all of our tutorials, you can go back and
			practice until you&apos;re comfortable with it. </description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
