<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Viewing time-related vessel tracks"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>Debrief offers more than just a static overview of vessel tracks, it also allows you to control the time period for data shown.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Open Navigator" skip="true">
		<description>If <b>Navigator</b> isn&apos;t visible, open it.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the sample plot-file">
		<description>Double-click on <b>sample.dpf</b> in the <b>Navigator</b> window and the sample plot will open.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Fit to window"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/moving_around.html#Fit_To_Win">
		<description>Click on the <b>Fit-to-Window</b> toolbar button to make all of the data visible.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="View the time controller"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/start_up.html#debrief_views">
		<description>We looked at the <b>Time Controller</b> in the <b>Filtering your view</b> tutorial previously; if it isn&apos;t currently visible, open it.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Confirm you are in normal Stepping mode time">
		<description> The Debrief <b>Time Controller</b> has two &apos;time stepping&apos; modes:
			<br/><b>1.</b> <b>Normal mode</b> shows all exercise data.
			<br/><b>2.</b> <b>Snail mode</b> shows the current position and recent
			points, and is used for detailed analysis around a specific time.
			<br/>Click on the left-most button to select <b>Normal mode</b>.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Move slowly through the data">
		<description>Above the current time indicator are a series of buttons similar to the
			pause/play/rewind buttons on any media player. Click on the buttons
			and you&apos;ll see the green <b>date and time</b> value adjust accordingly.
			<br/>Also note the movement of the white rectangle along the vessel tracks.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Move quickly through the time period">
		<description> If you want to move quickly through the time period, drag the time-slider in
			either direction and see how quickly the white highlight rectangle moves along the vessel
			tracks, as well as the time changein the <b>Time Controller</b> view.
			<br/>In addition, notice how the <b>Track Tote</b> view updates to reflect the current
			time (if it isn&apos;t open, open it and see).</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Experiment with the time format options"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/controlling_time.html#stepper_display_modes">
		<description> The <b>Time Controller</b> also has a drop-down menu at the end of the toolbar
			with additional sub-menus, including <b>DTG Format</b>, where you can select the current time display format; 
			and <b>Time Slider Increment</b>, where you can adjust
			the time increment used for moving through the plot.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Change the DTG format so that you
			can see the full Year/Month/Day for the current DTG (Note the year… yes, Debrief has
			been going for some time now).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Change the <b>Time Slider Increment</b> to 15 minutes, so
			that you can move through the plot more quicly.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Change plotting modes"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/controlling_time.html#relative_mode">
		<description>
			<i>NoPrint</i> Start off by reading through the online help on the time controllers
				<b>Plotting Modes</b> (via the above help link). Then have a play.
			<i>NoPrint</i>
			To change plotting modes:
			<br/><b>1.</b> In the <b>Time Controller</b> drop-down menu, click on <b>Plotting
			Mode</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Primary Centred/North Oriented</b>.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click the <b>Snail mode</b> button.
			Now move the slider forwards and backwards and watch the plot change.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> The <b>Plotting Mode</b> is selected independently of the mutually exclusive <b>Normal</b> and <b>Snail Display Modes</b>.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Work with time periods">
		<description> Now we&apos;ll look at the time period selector in the <b>Time Controller</b>. No
			prizes for guessing what this does.
			<br/>However, even though it is used to select a period
			of time, it doesn&apos;t function in quite the same way as the other controls do, where you see something happens because it&apos;s affecting &apos;current&apos;
			operations; when you change the time period you&apos;re changing the interval that will
			be used for &apos;subsequent&apos; operations.
			<br/>For example:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Select a time period of <b>120700</b> to
			<b>121000</b>.
			<br/><b>1.</b> From the <b>Time Controller</b> drop-down menu, select <b>Export calculated data to
			clipboard</b>.
			<br/>The 3 hours of calculated data from this selected period has just been
			copied to your system clipboard. You can now paste it into your preferred analysis software (such as Microsoft Excel).</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Control the visible time period">
		<description> It is easy to control the visible time period in Debrief:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Select the <b>120600</b> to <b>120700</b> period in the time plot.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the <b>Filter plot data
			to selected time period</b> button on the <b>Time Controller</b> toolbar (second from right).
			<br/>Now, when you move the time-slider, the plot is trimmed to that 1-hour period.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> holding down the <b>Shift</b> key makes the slider move in larger increments (you can even jump through the exercise in 1-hour blocks by holding down the <b>Shift</b> key when dragging the selected period).
			<br/>So you don&apos;t lose the sample data in this example, ensure you extend the sliders
			out to their full range to reveal all the training data.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Precise time selection">
		<description> It can be difficult to select precise times using the slider, but there is
			another way:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Double-click on the start/finish time marker triangle - the value will
			then become editable in the <b>Properties</b> view (below the <b>Time Controller</b>).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Modify the time value and then click outside the property box to enter the value.
			<br/>Or, if you&apos;re trying to move the time value a very small amount:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Press the <b>Ctrl</b> key on your keyboard
			<br/><b>2.</b> Double-click on the start/finish marker to display a mini time-slider.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Adjust it to the time you require, then click outside the box to enter this time value.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Time Controller editable properties">
		<description> As we&apos;ve already seen, the <b>Time Controller</b> drop-down menu contains a series
			of sub-menus. Some of these sub-menus have an <b>Edit properties</b> element which lets you
			control various aspects of temporal data analysis.
			<br/>For example, once you&apos;ve selected an
			item from the properties drop-down menu, its attributes will then become editable in the
			<b>Properties</b> view (open it if it&apos;s not visible).
			<br/>Note: the item only appears on the
			properties window if the <b>Time Controller</b> is the &apos;active&apos; view (blue highlighted name tab). If it isn&apos;t active,
			click on the tab to do so.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Bookmarking the current time ">
		<description> Debrief NG lets you insert a bookmark attached to a particular DTG in the
			current plot. This can be useful if you&apos;re analysing a particular exercise and
			want to record some interactions.
			<br/><b>1.</b> In <b>Normal</b> view mode, move the time-slider to <b>121011</b>
			hrs - The moment when &apos;Nelson&apos; (RED) initiates a manoeuvre in reaction to having detected &apos;Collingwood&apos; (BLUE).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select <b>Add DTG as bookmark</b> from the
			<b>Time-Controller</b> drop-down menu. A dialog box will open inviting you to add a remark
			for that DTG.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Enter “First contact", then press <b>OK</b>.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Now, move the time slider to <b>121131</b>.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Select <b>Add DTG as bookmark</b> again and enter a bookmark title "Plotlock start".
			<br/>These bookmarks won&apos;t be visible until you show the Bookmarks view:
			<br/><b>6.</b> Click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show view</b> > <b>Bookmarks</b>
			<br/><b>7.</b> Now, double-click on
			either bookmark to move to that time.
			<br/><b>8.</b> Save (<b>Ctrl+S</b>) and close your plot.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> you can store as many bookmarks as you like and they can be used across all your analysis
			plots.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
		<description>If you found the above tutorial easy, then great! Not only
			is the Time Controller a very capable panel that provides a wide range of functionality,
			but it&apos;s also one of the more complex parts of Debrief. So once you&apos;ve conquered it,
			you&apos;re really going great guns.</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
