<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Analysing time-related calculated data"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>Debrief is capable of producing analysis products far beyond the traditional
			graphical track plots. All it needs is the data. The most obvious derived products are
			the analysis plots: graphs showing time versus either a recorded data value or a
			calculation based on a specific set of data values. In this tutorial, we will look at
			how to do just that.</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Overview">
		<description> To be able to analyse the data correctly, we first need to tell Debrief what
			information we want, such as:
			<br/>• the time period we want plotted
			<br/>• which participants to plot data for
			<br/>• what type of data to plot
			<br/>• which is the primary track (for relative	calculations)
			<br/> But, before we can do any of this, we need the data...
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open Navigator" skip="true">
		<description>If <b>Navigator</b> isn&apos;t visible, open it.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the sample plot-file">
		<description>Double-click on <b>sample.dpf</b> in the <b>Navigator</b> window to open the sample plot.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Fit to window"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/moving_around.html#Fit_To_Win">
		<description> click on the <b>Fit-to-Window</b> toolbar button to make all of the data visible.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the Time Controller"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/controlling_time.html" skip="true">
		<description>
			As we said in step 1, one of the attributes we need to specify is the time period, and we need the <b>Time Controller</b> to do it. 
			<br/>If is isn&apos;t open, click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Time Controller</b>.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Select the desired time period"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/controlling_time.html#time_controller">
		<description>
			Now we need to select the required time period: adjust the start and end markers to select the period <b>120800</b> to <b>121100</b>. 
			<br/><b>Note:</b> remember that holding down the <b>shift</b> key makes the sliders snap to the hour markers.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the Outline View" href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/layer_mgr.html"
		skip="true">
		<description>Next we need to indicate what tracks we want to see information for. In the bottom left hand corner of Debrief you should find the <b>Outline View</b> window. If it isn&apos;t visible, click on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Outline View</b>.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Select the tracks of interest" dialog="true">
		<description>In the <b>Outline</b> window:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Click on the &apos;Collingwood&apos; track to select it.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Then hold down the <b>Ctrl</b> key and click on the &apos;Nelson&apos; track to select it as well. </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open xy-plot"
		href="/org.mwc.debrief.help/html/legacy/show_time_vars.html" dialog="true">
		<description> Now we will open the xy-plot:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click on the selected items and, in the
			drop-down menu, click on <b>View XY Plot</b>.
			<br/><b>2.</b> The <b>View time-variable plot</b> dialog will open;
			select <b>Range</b> from the available attributes.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Click on <b>OK</b> and the <b>Select primary</b> dialog
			will open.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Designate either <b>Track:Collingwood</b> or <b>Track:Nelson</b> as the primary
			track for this plot. For this example, select <b>Collingwood</b>.
			<br/>As Debrief calculates the data and relationships between multiple tracks, it
			needs to know which track is the primary subject to be able to do this.
			<br/><b>5.</b> The <b>Collingwood Range v Time plot</b> graph will appear on the screen. </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Navigate around the plot">
		<description> To navigate around the plot area:
			<br/>•  <b>Zoom in</b> - you can zoom in on the graph by
			dragging the mouse from top-left to bottom-right (or you can
			right-click and select <b>Zoom in</b> ><b>[Both axis | Domain axis | Range axis]</b>).
			<br/>•  <b>Zoom out</b> - you can zoom out by dragging the mouse from bottom-right to top-left. (or
			you can right-click and select <b>Zoom out</b> ><b>[Both axis | Domain axis | Range axis]</b>).
			<br/>•  Another method of zooming out is to click on the <b>Fit to Window</b> button
			- you&apos;ve already used this before.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> there are other ways of using the plot area,
			such as using the tab key to cycle through the drag modes (the buttons to the left
			of the <b>Zoom in</b> button on the main toolbar), or, if you have a mouse with a wheel, you
			can press the <b>Ctrl</b> key and then use the <b>mouse wheel</b> to zoom in and out of the plot
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Customise">
		<description>You can also experiment with the other commands, and even configure and customise the graph to use your preferred font and titles.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Track Other Objects">
		<description> It isn&apos;t just tracks that can be plotted, as you can also plot other objects,
			such as tracking the proximity of multiple vessels to a fixed point object (such as a
			sensor).
			<br/>To do this:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Insert a label annotation on the plot by clicking on <b>Drawing</b> >
			<b>Label</b>. A red marker will be placed on the plot called <b>Blank label</b>.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Click on the	<b>Properties View</b> tab and rename the label to &apos;Sensor 1&apos;.
			<br/>We will now move the sensor to a new position.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Press <b>Alt+3</b> on your keyboard to select the <b>Drag Whole Feature</b> option,
			the mouse cursor will change to a brown hand.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Move the mouse over <b>Sensor 1</b> until the
			hand changes to <b>green</b>. Now you can move the sensor.
			<br/><b>5.</b> Drag and drop it to wherever you
			wish on the plot, somewhere close to the 2 tracks perhaps.
			<br/><b>6.</b> Now, in the <b>Outline view</b>,
			left-click on <b>Sensor 1</b> if it is not selected.
			<br/><b>7.</b> Then <b>Ctrl+click</b> on <b>Collingwood</b> and <b>Nelson</b>.
			<br/><b>8.</b> Right-click and select <b>View xy plot</b>.
			<br/><b>9.</b> Select <b>Range</b> and click <b>OK</b>.
			<br/><b>10.</b> Designate <b>Label:Sensor 1</b> as the primary track and click on <b>OK</b>.
			<br/>You will now see the <b>Sensor 1 Range v Time plot</b> showing how close the vessels came to the sensor and at what
			times.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
		<description>That concludes the tutorial for conducting analyses using Debrief. If you&apos;re going to use Debrief to generate positional data for missing tracks, why not try the <b>Single Sided Reconstruction</b> tutorial.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
