<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Filtering your view" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>Ever-increasing data rates from multiple recording systems means your analysis
			plot will quickly become swamped. This tutorial will show you how to manage the volume
			and type of data displayed using the Debrief NG tools.
		</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Open Navigator">
		<description>You will need to have the <b>Navigator</b> view open; if it isn&apos;t visible, open it now
			(refer to the previous cheat sheet if you&apos;re still unsure on how to do this).
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open a sample file">
		<description>Now, double-click on the <b>sample.dpf</b> in the <b>Navigator</b> view and
			the sample Debrief plot will open. </description>
	</item>
	<item title="View the entire data plot area">
		<description>To ensure you can see all of the data, click on the <b>Fit-to-Window</b> button
			either on the main toolbar or in the <b>Chart Overview</b> panel.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the Outline View">
		<description>You will need the <b>Outline</b> view for this exercise, so open it now by either
			clicking on <b>Window</b> > <b>Show View</b> > <b>Outline</b>, or by using the shortcut key <b>Alt+Shift+Q</b>, <b>O</b>.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Hide shape">
		<description>At the top of the <b>Outline</b> view is a toolbar with functions that can be
			applied to plot items. In that view, you can see a list of items, including one called
				<b>Misc (5 items)</b>. Click on the arrow to the left of it to expand the group.
			<br/>Select any item in that group and click on the empty rectangle button in
			the <b>Outline</b> view toolbar(next to the <b>+2</b> button). You will see the tick next to the element
			and the corresponding shape on the plot disappear.
			<br/>Another way of doing this is to use the drop-down menu in the <b>Outline</b> view: this is accessed via the small arrow at the end of
			the <b>Outline</b> view toolbar (to the right of the ticked check-box).
			<br/>Note: you can show/hide more than one item at a time by holding down the <b>Ctrl</b> key and clicking on
			multiple items.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Hide whole layer">
		<description> Next, experiment with hiding whole layers: select one of the tracks in the
			<b>Outline</b> view and practice hiding and revealing it.
			<br/>Note: you can expand each track to
			see the series of positions within. Once expanded, you can select a series of points
			(each of which represents a time-period) to be hidden or revealed. However, this is just
			one way of doing it.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Filtering to a time period">
		<description> We will now filter the plot to a particular time period:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Open the <b>Time Controller</b> or make it active if it is already open. The
			lower section has a pair of sliders used to mark the start and end
			time of a variety of tasks.
			<br/><b>2.</b> In the drop-down menu of the <b>Time Controller</b> (the triangle on the right of the <b>Time Controller</b> toolbar), select <b>Filter to period</b>.
			<br/><b>3.</b> In the <b>time period markers</b> (under the slider), drag the start and stop markers to different positions. As you do
			this, you&apos;ll see the shaded portion adjust to the selected period: this represents a
			custom time period which is also visible on your plot. You can drag this shaded section to
			move your &apos;windows&apos; forwards and backwards.
			<br/>If you hold down the <b>Shift</b> key while you
			move elements on the time plot, they will ‘snap&apos; to the hour lines. </description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
