<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Analysing Sensor Data" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="..\contentFile.xsd">
	<intro>
		<description>With ever-increasing data rates from multiple recording
			systems it is easy for an analysis plot to become swamped. Debrief NG
			provides tools to reduce the volume and type of data displayed. This
			tutorial will lead you through the management of large volumes of
			data.</description>
	</intro>
	<item title="Check you have data" href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cnav.htm">
		<description>
			To check that you have data:
			<br/>Open <b>Navigator</b> (using your mouse, or <b>Ctrl+3</b> and typing &apos;navigator&apos;).
			<br/>Confirm you have sample data-files in navigator. If not, refer to the <b>Finding the sample data</b> cheat-sheet
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Open the sample sensor tracks file">
		<description>To open the sample file, double-click on the <b>sen_tracks.rep</b> file. 
			If the <b>Import</b> dialog appears, select &apos;Over The Ground&apos; for both tracks; you
			will see the red and blue vessel tracks.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Fit to window"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\moving_around.html#Fit_To_Win">
		<description>The workspace can get cluttered quickly; to make sure all of the data is visible, click on the <b>Fit-to-Window</b> toolbar button.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Add the SSK track">
		<description>We will now add the sensor data. Starting from the <b>Navigator</b> view, drag the <b>sen_ssk_sensor.dsf</b> SSK sensor data file onto the plot. You can accept the default options in the import wizard.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Add the FF track">
		<description>
			Next, drag the <b>sen_frig_sensor.dsf</b> SSK sensor data file onto the plot.
			<br/><b>Note:</b> the data will import, but there won&apos;t be any visible changes to the plot area.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="View the sensor data">
		<description> To view the sensor data, in the <b>Outline View</b>:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Expand the
			&apos;tree&apos; for the 2 tracks called <b>Frigate</b> and <b>New_SSK</b>. In each of these
			tracks you will see named blocks of sensor data.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Now, we need to make
			each block of sensor data visible, so click on one to select it, and then click on the
				<b>Reveal Selected Items</b> toolbar button. As you make each set of data visible,
			you should see its bearing fan appear in the plot area. Overall, there are six blocks of
			sensor data across the two tracks. </description>
	</item>
	<item title="Sensor formatting options" skip="true">
		<description>Sensor lines can be formatted to change their colour, their label, and the location of their label. This formatting can be applied to a single sensor line or a series of sensor lines.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Format the sensor data">
		<description>Next, we will simulate the formatting a series of bearing lines to represent
			the state of a particular sensor. From the <b>Outline View</b>:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Open the <b>NEW_SSK_BB</b> sensor for the <b>New_SSK</b> track (click on <b>New_SSK</b>, then on <b>Sensors</b> to show the sensor bearings).
			<br/><b>2.</b> Select the first five sensor bearings by left-clicking on the top sensor bearing;
			then, hold down the <b>Shift</b> key, click on the 5th sensor; all 5 items should be selected.
			<br/><b>3.</b> Switch to the <b>Properties</b> view to show the editable properties for those bearings.
			<br/><b>4.</b> Click on the <b>Color</b> property, select <b>yellow</b> and Click <b>Ok</b>.
			<br/>You will see the sensor lines on the plot update.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Conduct a plot-lock"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\formatting_data.html#track_shifting">
		<description>
			We will now simulate the process of dragging tracks so that their bearing fans match. In the UK this process is called a plot-lock, and in the US it&apos;s called a tie-point.
			<br/>First though, we must indicate which tracks we want to view the relationship between:
			<br/><b>1.</b> Right-click on <b>Frigate</b> and then select <b>Make Primary</b>
			<br/><b>2.</b> Right-click on <b>New_SSK</b> and select <b>Make Secondary</b>
			<br/>These will both appear in the Track Tote view.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Commence plot-lock"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\moving_around.html#toggle_buttons">
		<description>To commence plot lock which will enable us to use the mouse to drag the tracks, click on the <b>Drag Track Segment button</b> on the right side of the globe.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Start dragging"
		href="\org.mwc.debrief.help\html\legacy\formatting_data.html#stacked_dots_view">
		<description> The <b>Stacked Dots</b> view should have opened and the cursor should now have
			changed to a brown hand.
			<br/>The <b>Stacked Dots</b> view shows the bearing error for visible
			sensor bearing lines against the point on the target track nearest to that DTG.
			<br/>When the cursor is over the end of a track, it will turn green.
			<br/><b>1.</b> Move the cursor over the north-west end of the blue track until the cursor turns green.
			<br/><b>2.</b> Hold down the mouse button and start dragging the track. You will see the track and its sensor data start
			to hover as you drag it, and the bearing errors in the <b>Stacked Dots</b> view will update
			proportionally. In plot-locking the tracks, you&apos;re trying to minimise the errors
			displayed on the graph. If you value some sensor data more than others, experiment with
			hiding the other blocks of sensor data (by making them invisible) - this will unclutter
			the plot and the stacked dots, making plot-locking easier.</description>
	</item>
	<item title="Done">
		<description> Well done! You&apos;ve completed the steps on loading, managing, and formatting
			sensor data - supported by a healthy dose of plot-locking.
			<br/>Having come this far, you now
			know the initial steps of using Debrief. Sure, you&apos;re not a master yet, but that comes
			with a bit of practice, so be sure to run through the steps above again.
			<br/>You now know
			about the views, and how to use them to your advantage, so it won&apos;t take you as long
			next time. Now we&apos;ll move on the next cheat sheet, <b>Using Debrief in Analysis</b>.
		</description>
	</item>
</cheatsheet>
