<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compositeCheatsheet name="Getting some data into Debrief NG">
   <taskGroup name="Getting started with Debrief NG" skip="false">
      <intro>
         This series of cheatsheets will guide you through creating your Debrief working environment, customising it according to your preferred file locations, and loading some analysis data.
      </intro>
      <taskGroup kind="sequence" name="Defining your workspace" skip="false">
         <intro>
            In comparison with prior versions of Debrief, Debrief NG introduces the concept of a Workspace - a central repository for your assorted analysis-related documents.  Within this workspace your work is grouped into individual projects: thus you can quickly switch between concurrent analysis tasks.  Debrief&apos;s provision of projects alows you to quickly drag and drop Debrief data-files and plots.
         </intro>
         <onCompletion>
            Right, Debrief now knows where to find your data.  In the next series of steps you will load and examine some data.
         </onCompletion>
         <task kind="cheatsheet" name="Generating a project" skip="false">
            <intro>
               Right, we&apos;ll start off by creating a Project that will contain our work
            </intro>
            <onCompletion>
               You&apos;ve now created a project into which you can store your Debrief data
            </onCompletion>
            <param name="id" value="org.mwc.debrief.help.started.generate_project">
            </param>
            <param name="showIntro" value="true">
            </param>
         </task>
         <task kind="cheatsheet" name="Finding your data" skip="false">
            <intro>
               If you already have one or more folders containing Debrief data, you can add them to your Debrief NG project (or load sample data that was installed within Debrief NG)
            </intro>
            <onCompletion>
               You can now repeat this process to create links to your other Debrief data directories.
            </onCompletion>
            <param name="id" value="org.mwc.debrief.help.started.existing_data">
            </param>
         </task>
      </taskGroup>
      <taskGroup kind="sequence" name="Viewing some data" skip="false">
         <intro>
            This series of steps will guide you through creating then populating a new Debrief plot.
         </intro>
         <task kind="cheatsheet" name="Creating a new plot" skip="false">
            <intro>
               We will now use Debrief&apos;s New Plot wizard to create a plot ready for import of data-files.
            </intro>
            <onCompletion>
               Note that we didn&apos;t have to use the wizard steps, we could have inserted chart features into our Plot by hand using the Chart Features menu.
            </onCompletion>
            <param name="id" value="org.mwc.debrief.help.started.create_plot">
            </param>
         </task>
         <task kind="cheatsheet" name="Importing some existing data" skip="false">
            <intro>
               Debrief NG stores it&apos;s user data in collections named projects.
            </intro>
            <param name="id" value="org.mwc.debrief.help.started.loading_data">
            </param>
         </task>
         <task kind="cheatsheet" name="Learn more about the UI" skip="false">
            <intro>
               Here you&apos;ll learn more about the Debrief user interface
            </intro>
            <param name="path" value="ViewHelpForUI.xml">
            </param>
         </task>
      </taskGroup>
   </taskGroup>
</compositeCheatsheet>
